In May 1980,Fidel Castro opened the harbor at Moriel, Cuba
1980年5月，卡斯特罗开放了古巴玛利尔的港口
with the apparent intention of letting some of his people
他的意图相当明显,就是让一些人民
join their relatives in the United States.
和在美国的亲人团聚
Within seventh-two hours,3000 U.S. boats were headed for Cuba.
短短72小时之内，有三千艘美国船只开往古巴
It soon became evident that Castro was forcing the boat owners
但很快的证据显示，卡斯特罗逼迫船主
to carry back with them not only their relatives,
除了接走亲戚之外
but the dregs of his jails.
也要载古巴监狱中的人渣
Of the 125,000 refugees that landed in Florida
在抵达佛罗里达的二万五千个难民当中
an estimated 25,000 had criminal records.
估计有两万五千名有刑事犯罪纪录
...they are unwilling to adapt to the spirit of our revolution...
他们不愿意适应我们的革命精神…
We don't want them! We don't want them!
我们不要他们！我们不要他们！
MARIEL HARBOR, CUBA
古巴玛利尔港
What do you call yourself, huh?
你叫什么？
Antonio Montana.And you, what you call yourself?
安东尼奥蒙大拿. 你呢？
-Where'd you learn English, Tony?  -In school.
-你在哪里学的英文，东尼？ -学校
And my father, he was from the United States.
也跟我爸学，他是美国人
Just like you, you know?
跟你一样，你知道吗？
He was a Yankee.
他是洋基人
He used to take me a lot to the movies.
他以前常带我去看电影
I learned.
我就学会了
I watch the guys like Humphrey Bogart, James Cagney.
我看过亨弗莱鲍嘉跟詹姆斯卡格尼
They teach me to talk. I like those guys.
他们教我说英文，我喜欢他们
I always know one day I'm coming here, United States.
我早就知道有一天我会来美国
-So where's your old man now?  -He dead. He die.
-那你老头呢？ -死了
Sometime. Somewhere.
在某事某地
-Mother?  -She dead, too.
-你妈呢？ -也死了
-What kind of work you do in Cuba?  -You know, things.
-你在古巴做哪行的？ -你知道啦，一些事
I was this, that.
这个做点，那个做点
Construction business.
建筑业
I work a lot with my hands. I was in the Army.
我干很多劳力活，我曾经是陆军
Any family in the States? Cousins, brother-in-law, anybody?
在美国有家人吗？表亲，姻亲，任何亲戚？
Nobody. Everybody's dead.
没有，大家都死了
You ever been to jail, Tony?
坐过牢吗，东尼？
Me? Jail? No way, no.
我？坐牢？不可能
-Been in a mental hospital?  -Oh, yeah. On the boat coming over.
-进过精神病院吗？ -有啊，过来的那艘船就是
What about homosexuality, Tony? You like men, huh?
你是同性恋吗，东尼？你喜欢男人吗？
You like to dress up like a woman?
你喜欢打扮成女人的样子吗？
What is wrong with this guy? He kidding me or what?
这家伙有问题啊？他在开玩笑吗？
Just answer the questions, Tony.
回答问题，东尼
Okay. No.
好吧，不是
Fuck, no.
妈的，不是
Arrested for vagrancy? Marijuana?
有没有因为流浪或是大麻被捕？
-Never, man. -Heroin?
-从来没有 -海洛因呢？
-Cocaine?  -No.
-古柯碱呢？ -没有
Where'd you get the beauty scar, tough guy? Eating pussy?
这条疤怎么来的，好家伙？和女人胡搞吗？
How am I gonna get a scar like that eating pussy?
和女人胡搞怎么会有条疤？
This was when I was a kid, you know?
是小时候伤到的，你知道吗？
You should see the other kid. You can't recognize him.
你该看看另一个小孩，他简直不成人样了
And this?
这个呢？
What? That's nothing. That's from my sweetheart.
那个？这没什么，是我甜心弄的
Sweetheart, my ass! We've been seeing more and more of these.
甜心个鬼！我们最近常常看到这个
Some kind of code these guys used in the can.
这些家伙在监狱里的某种代号
Pitchfork means an assassin or something.
干草叉代表刺客之类的
You want to tell us about it
你要跟我们说说
or you want to take a trip to the detention center?
还是想到拘留所去转转？
Okay, you got me.
好吧，你赢了
I was in the can one time.For buying dollars. Big deal.
我是坐过牢，为了买美金，没什么大不了的
-That's pretty funny, Tony.  -That's true.
-真好笑，东尼  -是真的
It was a Canadian tourist.
是个加拿大游客
Did you mug him first? Get him out of here!
你是不是先抢了他？带他出去！
-Come on!  -So I fuck up!
-走吧！ -我搞砸了！
Let me talk to this guy.Please! Let me talk to him a minute.
让我和他谈谈，拜托！让我和他谈一分钟
You a Communist?
你是共产党吗？
How'd you like it?
你喜欢共产党吗？
They tell you always what to do, what to think, what to feel.
他们总是告诉你该怎么做，该怎么想，该怎么感觉
Do you want to be like a sheep? Like all those other people?
你想和只绵羊一样吗？和其它人一样？
I don't have to listen to this!
我不需要听这些！
You wanna work 8, 10 fucking hours? You own nothing, you got nothing!
你想要工作八到十小时吗？你什么都没有！
Do you want a chivato on every corner,
你想要每个街口都有警方线人
watching everything you do?
监视你的一举一动？
Everything you say, man?
监听你说的每一句话？
You know I eat octopus three times a day?
你知道我餐餐都是吃章鱼吗？
I got fucking octopus coming out of my ears.
吃到章鱼都快从喉咙里满出来了
I got fucking Russian shoes, my feet's coming through.
我穿的是俄罗斯鞋，鞋底都穿洞了
How'd you like that?
你喜欢吗？
You want me to stay there and do nothing?
你要我待在这里，什么事都不做？
I'm no fucking criminal, man. I'm no puta or thief.
我不是罪犯，我不是皮条客，也不是小愉
I'm Tony Montana, a political prisoner from Cuba.
我是东尼蒙大拿，古巴的政治犯
I want my fucking human rights, now!
我要我的人权，现在就要！
Like President Jimmy Carter says. Okay?
就像卡特总统说的
Carter should see this human right. He's really good.
卡特应该见见这位要求人权的家伙，他听来很有说服力
-What do you say?  -I don't believe any of this shit!
-你说呢？ -我一点都不信！
They all sound alike to me.That Castro is shitting all over us.
他们说的都差不多，卡斯特罗把我们整惨了
Send the bastard to Freedom Town. Let them see him.
送这个王八蛋去自由城，让他们看看他
-Get him out of here.  -You know something?
-带他出去  -你知道吗？
You can send me anywhere.
你送我哪都一样
Here, there, this, that. It don't matter.
这里、那里都一样
There's nothing you can do to me that Castro hasn't done...
不论你对我做什么，卡斯特罗都先做过了…
Get him out of here!
带他出去！
-So?  -So?
-所以？  -所以？
What'd you tell them?
你跟他们说了什么？
What you told me to tell them. That we... I was in sanitation.
你叫我跟他们说的东西，说我在营养院
They didn't go for it.
他们不相信
-Sanitation?  -Yeah.
-营养院？ -嗯
I told you to tell them you was in a sanitarium, not sanitation.
我叫你跟他们说疗养院，不是营养院
-Sanitarium. Yeah.  -You didn't tell me that.
-疗养院  -你不是这么说的
No, I told you to say you had TB and you was in a sanitarium.
我跟你说你有肺结核，住在疗养院
You was cured.
你后来痊愈了
-When did you tell me that?  -You should've kept your mouth shut.
-你几时跟我说的？  -你应该闭嘴的
They'd think you was a horse and let you out.
他们可能会以为你是一匹马，就把你给放了
ONE MONTH LATER
一个月后
Tony! Montana!
东尼！蒙大拿！
Tony Montana! Come here.
东尼蒙大拿！过来
Come here, man. I gotta talk to you.
过来，我有话跟你说
Come on, man. It's important.
过来，很重要的事
-So close, man.   -Come on.
-就差一点  -拜托
-I gotta talk to you.  -Where are you going?
-我得和你谈谈  -你要去哪里？
-Leave him alone.  -I got better things to do.
-别烦他  -我有要紧的事要做
You're chicken, man. You almost made it.
你这胆小鬼，你差点就得分了
Are you ready for some good news?
准备好要听好消息了吗？
Sure. What you got, man?
当然，什么好消息？
We can be outta this place in 30 days.
我们三十天内就可以离开这里
Not only that, but we got a green card and a job in Miami.
不只这样，我们会有绿卡，还有一份在迈阿密的工作
Now are we made or are we made, man?
我们真是太好运，老兄？
What do we gotta do? Go to Cuba and hit the Beard?
我们要做什么？去古巴打大胡子吗？
-No, man, somebody else.  -You're kidding.
-不是，老兄，是别人  -你开玩笑
-No.  -You're not kidding?
-没有  -你没开玩笑？
Guy named Rebenga, man. Emilio Rebenga.
一个叫里本嘉的家伙，艾米利奥里本嘉
Rebenga?
里本嘉？
-I know that name.  -Yeah?
-我听过这个名字  -真的？
-He's political.  -Yeah.
-他是政治犯  -喔
Well, he's coming in here today. Castro just sprung him.
他今天来这里，卡斯特罗刚刚放逐他
This guy was one of the top dogs for Fidel in the early days.
他是卡斯楚特罗早期的左右手之一
Castro felt he couldn't trust him and threw him in jail.
卡斯特罗觉得无法再信任他，就把他丢到牢里
But while he was on top, he tortured a few guys to death.
但是在他当红时，他把几个人严刑折磨到死
One of the guy's brothers is a rich guy in Miami now.
其中一个人的兄弟，现在是迈阿密的有钱人
He wants the favor repaid.
他想要还这个人情
That's where we come in.
这时就轮到我们出场了
It's ugly, man.
不是个开心的任务
Yeah.
嗯
You tell your guys in Miami, your friend,
你跟你迈阿密的朋友说
it'd be a pleasure.
我很高兴接下任务
I'd kill a Communist for fun,
我可以为了开心而杀一个共产党
but for a green card, I gonna carve him up real nice.
但是有绿卡可拿，我会做得更加专业
MIAMI, FLORIDA,AUGUST 11, 1980(UPI)... HUNDREDS OF CUBAN REFUGEES
1980年8月11日，在佛罗里达的迈阿密，数百名古巴难民
BEGAN RIOTING THIS MORNING AT A DETENTION CENTER SITUATED
今早在位于北迈阿密95号公路下的拘留中心
UNDER INTERSTATE 95 IN NORTH MIAMI, BURNING TENTS AND ATTACKING
展开暴动，放火烧帐篷
IMMIGRATION AND NATUNALIZATION GUARDS WITH PIPER, STICKS, AND ROCKS.
用棍棒和石头攻击移民局警卫
Rebenga!
里本嘉！
From a friend you fucked!
一个被你害过的朋友向你问好！
That face. That's nice.
那张脸，真帅
-That doesn't look like me.  -That looks pretty, man.
-看起来一点也不像我   -很漂亮，老兄
小哈瓦那餐厅
Fuck!
干！
What's wrong, man?
怎么了，老兄？
Your big shot friend better come up with something soon.
你那个大人物朋友最好快点帮我们找个好点的工作
I didn't come to the U.S. To break my fucking back.
我可不是来美国做苦工的
He's coming! What do you want from me?
他在想办法了！不然你想要我怎样？
Fucking thing!
烂东西！
I told you.
我跟你说了
What's wrong?
又怎么了？
小哈瓦那
Look at that one.
看看那个
That one in the pink. She's beautiful.
穿粉红色那个，她好漂亮
Look at those titties.
看看那对奶子
Look at that punk with her.
看看她身边的混混
What's he got that I don't have?
我哪一点比不上他？
Well, he's very handsome, for one thing, you know?
他很帅，这是其一，你知道吗？
I mean, look at the way he dresses.
看看他穿成什么样子
Come on. That's style, flash, pizzazz.
拜托，那叫品味、流行、时尚
And a little coke money doesn't hurt nobody.
有几个毒钱就更好了
Look at this.
看看这个
Fucking onions.
烂洋葱
They ought to be picking gold from the street.
他们一定是在街上捡到黄金
Oh, God, I can feel it.
老天，我感觉得出来
There's two guys looking for you out there.
外面有两个人找你
That's him, man. That's El mono. I told you.
就是他，那个猴子，我跟你说过了
Don't stay too fucking long.
别去太久
We've got a lot of work to do.
我们还有很多事要做
Waldo! Good to see you, man.
瓦度！见到你真好，老兄
This is my friend Tony Montana I've been telling you about.
这是我朋友东尼蒙大拿，我跟你提过
Tony, that's Omar Suarez, and that's Waldo Rojas over there.
东尼，那是奥马尔苏亚雷斯，那是瓦度罗杰斯
I got something for you.
我有事让你做
Yeah? What do we gotta do?
是吗？什么东西？
Gotta unload a boat.Marijuana. 45 tons. You get 500 each.
去船上搬货，是大麻，有25吨，一人五百元
-500? That's great.   -You gotta be kidding.
-五百？太好了   -你一定是在开玩笑
500?
五百？
Who do you think we are, baggage handlers?
你以为我们是谁？行李搬运工吗？
The going rate on a boat is 1,000 a night.
现在船上的价码是一晚一千元
You know that.
你知道的
First you gotta work your way up to 500.
你刚开始只能拿五百
What I did for you in Freedom Town, what was that?
我在自由城帮你做的，那算是什么？
That Rebenga hit was a game of dominoes?
你以为杀里本嘉是玩游戏吗？
-That was something else.   -Shut up! Take it easy.
-那是两回事  -闭嘴！放轻松
What's with this dishwasher, chico?
这个洗碗的是怎么了，小子？
Don't he know we could've got any space cadet to hit Rebenga cheaper?
难道他不知道我们可以找任何一个无名小卒来做掉里本嘉？
-50 bucks!   -Then why didn't you?
-五十块就够了！ -那你怎么不那么做？
Don't call me no fucking dishwasher, or I'll kick your monkey ass.
别再他妈的叫我洗碗工，否则我会踢你的猴子屁股
Who the fuck are you?
你他妈的以为自己是谁？
You can't do that, man!
你不可以这样，老兄！
The Colombians!
那个哥伦比亚人！
Okay, all right, big man!
好，大人物！
You want to make some big bucks? Let's see how tough you are.
你想赚大钱！让我看看你有多能干
You know something about cocaine?
你知道古柯碱吗？
You kidding me or what?
你在说笑吗？
There's a bunch of Colombians coming in Friday.
有几个哥伦比亚人星期五会过来
New guys. They say they got two keys for us, for openers.
新面孔，他们说首次交易会给我们两公斤的货
Pure coke. Hotel in Miami Beach. I want you to go over there.
纯古柯碱，在迈阿密海滩的旅馆，我要你过去
If it's what they say, pay them and bring it back.
如果他们说的是实话，付钱把货拿回来
Do that, you got 5 grand.
事成之后，你可以拿到五千元
Go, pay them, bring it back, yeah?
去，付钱，把货拿回来？
You know how to handle a machine gun?
你会用机关枪吗？
Yeah, man. We were in the Army.
会，我们以前是陆军
-You gonna need a couple other guys.   -That's no problem.
-你还需要几个人手  -那不是问题
Be at Hector's bodega at noon, Friday.
星期五中午，到海克托的酒店
You get the buy money then.
那时会把交易的钱给你
If anything happens to that buy money,
如果那笔钱出了意外
my boss will stick your heads up your asses
我老板会让你死得很难看
faster than a rabbit gets fucked!
比鬼还难看！
I'm scared.
我好怕
-You're pushing your luck.   -Don't worry.
-你刚刚是在玩火  -别担心
-That was dumb.  -You worry too much.
-那很蠢  -你担心得太多了
You'll have a heart attack.
你会得心脏病
You act like that guy's doing you a favor or something.
你表现得好像那家伙帮了你一个大忙
-What's this with the Colombians?   -What does it matter?
-哥伦比亚人是怎么回事？  -有分别吗？
He says "Colombians," and you make these eyes...
他一说“哥伦比亚人”，你就翻了个白眼…
I don't like fucking Colombians, okay?
我不喜欢哥伦比亚人，行了吧？
What you guys doing?
你们在干什么？
There's a lot of dishes to be washed.
还有一堆碗要洗
Wash them yourself.
你自己洗吧
I retire!
我退休了！
What the fuck you gonna do now?
你现在他妈的打算怎么办？
-Don't come back here!   -I gotta look after my investment!
-别回来这里！ -我要照顾我的投资！
-Fuck you guys!   -Close the shop!
-去你们的！ -关店吧！
卡莱尔
Look at those tits. She's begging for it.
看看那奶子，她正在求人睡她
Are you fucking crazy? She's 103 years old.
你疯了吗？她有103岁了吧
Not that one, man! That one!
不是那个，老兄！是那个！
-Which one?   -The young one.
-哪个？ -年轻那个
Move the fucking car. We're at a stop sign.
把这车两他妈的车开走，这里是马路口
We're just staying loose up here. You gotta stay loose.
我们在这里放松一下，你要放松点
You can't worry. You'll have a heart attack.
你别担心，你就快得心脏病了
-Just play it cool. Miami Beach.   -Miami Beach, man!
-轻松点，这里是迈阿密海滩  -迈阿密海滩，老兄！
The money stays in the trunk till I come out.
钱摆在后车厢里，直到我回来为止
You got it? Me, nobody else. Okay.
听到了吗？只有我，懂吧
I'm not out in 15 minutes, something's wrong. Okay?
如果我十五分钟内没回来，就表示出事了，懂吗？
-Room 9. You ready?   -Sure thing.
-九号房，准备好了吗？ -当然
Okay. You mind leaving the door open?
行了，你不介意把门开着吧
So my brother-in-law sees everything's okay.
这样我妹夫才能看到一切平安
Sure. No problem.
当然，没问题
No problem.
没问题
Hello. This is Marta.
你好，这是马耳他
Marta, hello.
马耳他，你好
I am Hector.
我是海克托
And I am Tony.
我是东尼
So, Omar says you're okay.
奥马尔说你不错
Yeah? Good. Omar's okay.
是吗？很好，奥马尔也不错
Okay.
好
So, you got the money?
钱带来了吗？
You got the stuff?
货带来了吗？
Sure I have the stuff, but not right here with me now.
货当然带来了，但不在我身边
I got it close by.
我放在附近
I don't have the money either, man.
钱也不在我身上
I have it close by, too.
我也放在附近
Where?
哪里？
In the car?
车上？
-No, not in the car, man.   -No?
-没有，不在车里  -没有？
How about you? Where you have your stuff?
那你呢？你东西放在哪里？
Not far.
不远
Okay. You want me to come in? We start over again?
好吧，你要我再进来一次？我们重新来过？
Where you from, Tony?
你是哪来的，东尼？
What the fuck difference does it make where I'm from?
我哪里来的有什么他妈的关系？
Take it easy, man.
放轻松点，老兄
I just want to get to know who I do business with.
我只是想知道我在和谁打交道
You'll know me once you do business with me and stop fucking around.
你和我交易之后就会知道了，别再他妈的玩花样
Okay?
可以吗？
- What's the story?   - Tony!
-怎么了？ -东尼！
You know, Frog Face, you just fucked yourself.
青蛙脸，你刚刚摆了自己一道
-You steal from me, you're dead.   -Yeah?
-敢偷我的东西你就死定了  -是吗？
You want to give me the cash,
你要把钱给我
or do I kill your brother first
还是要我先把你弟弟做了
before I kill you?
再把你也做了？
Why don't you try sticking your head up your ass?
你何不试试把头塞进自己的屁眼？
See if it fits.
看看合不合适
Yeah? Okay.
是吗？好
-Yeah, it's very important.   -I understand it's important.
-是，这很重要  -我知道这很重要
- Thank you.  - You're welcome.
-谢谢  -不客气
You forecasted an earthquake
你预测今早会有
in the 3-to-4-point range this morning.
三到四级的地震
We had an earthquake in the 3-to-4-point range.
真的发生三到四级的地震
-I'm impressed.   -Thank you, sir.
-让我印象深刻  -谢谢
However, isn't it rather slender evidence...
然而，证据不是很薄弱…
You have such beautiful skin.
你皮肤真好
I like the way you...
我喜欢你…
I don't know what I'm supposed to do today, but...
我不知道今天该做什么，不过…
Antonio, mira!
安东尼奥，看！
Watch what happens to your friend.
看看你的朋友发生了什么事
If you don't want this to happen to you,
如果你不想要同样的事发生在你身上
give me the money.
就把钱给我
Come on, come on.
拜托，别这样
Now the leg, huh.
现在轮到脚了
Let's do it, man. Come on.
我们上去吧，老兄，走吧
We're all gonna be all right.
我们会没事的
Okay, cara cicatriz.
好了，疤面
You can die, too. It makes no difference to me.
你也可以死，对我来说没什么不同
Last chance, pendejo!
最后一次机会，傻子！
Fuck you!
去你的！
-You okay?   -Yeah, man. It went in and out.
-你还好吗？ -没事，子弹射穿了
Okay, take him out of here, quick!
把他弄出去，快！
Chi Chi! Get the yeyo.
小奇！把东西拿走
-Your turn.   -I kill you!
-轮到你了  -我杀了你！
Die!
死吧！
Hurry up! Get in! Come on. Let's go!
快点！上车！快，走了！
Close the door!
关门！
Bunch of cowboys. Somebody fucked up.
一群牛仔，有人搞砸了
Yeah, well, I'll check it out right away.
嗯，我立刻去查
You do that, Omar. You do that.
你去查吧，奥马尔
-You still got the money?   -Yeah.
-钱还在你手上吗？  -嗯
And I got the yeyo.
货也在我手上
-You got the yeyo?   -Yeah, right.
-货在你手上？ -是，没错
-Bring it here.   -Fuck you.
-把东西拿过来  -去你妈的
I'm taking it to Lopez myself.
我会自己交给罗培兹
Not you, me.
不是你，是我
Nice fucking guy.
好个王八蛋
Frank Lopez. Tony Montana.
法兰克罗培兹，东尼蒙大拿
-Tony Montana.   -Mr. Lopez. It's a real pleasure.
-东尼蒙大拿  -罗培兹先生，真是荣幸
You can call me Frank.
你可以叫我法兰克
Everybody calls me Frank. My Little League team,
大家都叫我法兰克，我的小联盟球队
even the fucking prosecutors around town,
甚至镇上他妈的检察官
they all call me Frank.
都叫我法兰克
-Okay, Frank.   -How are you?
-好吧，法兰克  -你好吗？
Manny Ribera.
曼尼里贝拉
-He caught one on the job.   -Went right through.
-他在办事时吃了一颗子弹  -射穿了
We heard about that.
我们听说了
Omar, he tells me great things about you guys.
奥马尔，他跟我说了很多你们的好话
Well, Omar's okay.
奥马尔人不错
Not to mention, of course, the nice job you did for me.
更不用提你们帮我办的大事
-That Commie son of a bitch...  -You don't have to mention that.
-那个共产王八… -你不需要提这件事
-That was fun.   -That was fun?
-那很好玩  -很好玩？
-Damn right.   -That was fun.
-没错  -很好玩
Sometimes it's fun.
有时是很好玩的
What do you want to drink? Scotch, gin, rum? What do you like?
你想喝什么？威士忌、琴酒、兰姆酒？喜欢哪样？
Gin is fine. Want some? Two gins.
琴酒好了，要来点吗？两杯琴酒
I need a guy with steel in his balls, Tony.
我需要有胆识的人，东尼
A guy like you. And I need him around me all the time.
像你这样的人，我需要他随时在我身边
You, Tony, and your compadre here.
你，东尼和你的好友
Here's the stuff.
东西在这
Two keys.
两公斤
It cost my friend Angel his life. Here's the money.
我朋友安吉为此赔上一条命，钱在这
My gift to you.
我送你的礼物
I'm sorry about your friend, Tony.
你的朋友的事，我很抱歉，东尼
If people would do business the right way,
如果大家都用正常的方法做生意
there'd be no fuck-ups like this.
就不会发生这种错误
Don't think I don't appreciate the gesture.
别以为我不感谢你的表现
You're gonna find, you stay loyal in this business,
你会发现，只要你忠心
you're gonna move up. You're gonna move up fast.
你会往上爬，会很快往上爬
And you'll find out your biggest problem
你会发现你最大的麻烦
is not bringing in the stuff,
不是怎么把货拿到手
but what to do with all the fucking cash!
而是怎么花那些他妈的钱！
I hope I have that problem someday.
我希望我有一天会有这样的麻烦
You'll have that problem, don't worry.
你会有这样的麻烦的，别担心
Sit down over here.
过来坐下
Where the hell's Elvira? It's late. Go find her, will you?
艾薇拉死哪去了？很晚了，去找她，请你去找她好吗？
Jesus! Fucking broad.
老天！他妈的女人
She spends half her life dressing, the other half undressing.
她一半的人生都用来穿衣服，另一半时间则在脱衣服
Gotta get her in between.
你要在她穿脱之间找到她
-She's coming.   -Yeah.
-她来了  -嗯
You gotta jump on her when she's not looking.
你要趁她不注意占她便宜
That's the best time.
那太棒了
What are you guys doing tonight?
你们今晚有什么事做？
You wanna go to a nice restaurant with me? You hungry?
要不要和我去一间不错的餐厅？你饿了没？
I could eat a horse.
我饿到可以吃一头牛
-Okay, they'll cook you a horse.    -I'll eat it.
-好，就让他们给你煮头牛  -我一定吃掉
Tell me, where'd they get you? Right there in the side?
告诉我，他们打到你哪里？在侧边吗？
It's nothing. It went right through me.
没什么，子弹射过我的身体
It hit the wall.
打到墙上
I ran out of bullets, like an asshole.
我子弹用光了，像个白痴一样
When I changed the clip, a guy who I thought I killed
当我换弹夹时，那个我以为已经被我做掉的家伙
wasn't dead and shot me.
结果不但没死，还开枪射我
The guy was behind me. I killed him.
那家伙在我后面，我杀了他
-How many bullets you catch?   -Bullets? One bullet.
-你被几颗子弹射中？  -子弹？一颗
9mm.
九毫米口径的
Elvira, where the hell you been? It's 10:00. I'm starving.
艾薇拉，你跑哪去了？十点了，我饿死了
You're always hungry. You should try starving.
你一天到晚都在饿，你该试试饿死的滋味
Where you going? Come on.
你去哪里？
Come over here! I want you to meet a friend of mine.
过来这里！我给你介绍几个朋友
Tony Montana. Elvira.
东尼蒙大拿 艾薇拉
-Hello.   -Manny Ribera. Elvira.
-哈啰  -曼尼里贝拉，艾薇拉
So, there are five of us. Where are we having dinner?
我们有五个人，要去哪里吃晚饭？
I thought we'd go to the Babylon Club.
我打算去巴比伦俱乐部
-Again?    -Again.
-又去那里？ -又去那里
You know, Frank, if anyone wanted to assassinate you,
法兰克，如果有人想暗杀你
you wouldn't be too hard to find.
要找到你应该不会太难
Assassinate me? Who the hell would want to kill me?
暗杀我？有谁会想暗杀我？
I got nothing but friends!
我什么都没有，就只有朋友！
You never know. Maybe the catcher on your Little League team.
谁知道，或许是你小联盟球队的捕手
The catcher? That son of a bitch, he didn't get a base hit all season.
捕手？那个混蛋一整季都没上过垒
I should kill him!
我真该杀了他！
巴比伦俱乐部
You know who that is? Luis and Miguel Echevierra.
你知道那是谁吗？露伊丝和米格尔伊发利亚
They got the biggest distribution setup from here to Houston,
他们拥有最大的销售系统，从这里到德州的休斯敦
Tucson, all down that way.
到亚利桑纳州的图森，一路过去
What do you think of that, huh?
你觉得怎样？
Look.
看
You see that fat bastard? That's Nacho Contreras.
你看到那个死胖子吗？那是纳求康崔拉
El Gordo!
肥仔！
He's got more cash than anybody in this place.
他是这里最有钱的人
He's a real chazer!
他是不折不扣的凯泽！
You know what a chazer is?
你知道凯泽是什么吗？
No, Frank, you tell me. What is a chazer?
不知道，法兰克，你告诉我，凯泽是什么？
It's the Yiddish word for "pig."
是犹太话“猪”的意思
A guy who wants more than he needs.He don't fly straight no more.
一个贪婪无厌的人，他的行为不再正直
So, it comes down to one thing,Tony boy, and you never forget it.
结论就是东尼小子，永远不要忘记
Lesson Number 1:
第一课
Don't underestimate
不要低估
the other guy's greed!
别人会有多贪心！
Lesson Number 2:
第二课
Don't get high on your own supply.
别拿自己的货来用
That's right. Lesson Number 2: Don't get high on your own supply.
没错，第二课，别拿自己的货来用
Course, not everybody follows the rules.
当然不是每个人都遵守规则
Your champagne, Mr. Lopez.
您的香槟，罗培兹先生
-That is '64?   -The best, Mr. Lopez.
-是64年份的吗？ -是最好的，罗培兹先生
Omar, you pour it, and you bring another bottle right away, will you?
奥马尔，你来倒，下一瓶就轮到你来倒了，好吗？
Pleasure, Mr. Lopez.
我的荣幸，罗培兹先生
$550 for this bottle, Tony. What do you think of that?
这瓶要550元，东尼，你觉得怎么样？
-That's pretty good.   -For a bunch of fucking grapes.
-很不错  -以一堆他妈的葡萄来说
So, here's to old friends and to new friends.
敬老朋友和新朋友
How you like it, Tony?
你喜欢吗，东尼？
-That's good, Frank.   -That's good?
-很不错，法兰克  -很不错？
-Like you say, man.   -That's good!
-你说得没错，兄弟  -很不错！
I'm gonna get you new clothes, too.
我也要帮你买新衣服
I'm gonna get you $550 suits,
我会帮你买550元一套的西装
so you look real sharp.
让你看来很有型
'Cause I want you to work for me.
因为我要你帮我做事
I want you and your boys to work with Omar here.
我要你和你朋友在这里和奥马尔一起工作
We are going to do something big next month.
下个月我们有笔大生意
We are running a string of mules from Colombia.
我们会有一批骡子从哥伦比亚上来
You do good on that, there'll be some other things.
你把这件事办好，会有更多好东西等着你
That sounds like fun to me, Frank.
听起来不错，法兰克
You want a cigar?
要来根雪茄吗？
You wanna dance, Frank, or sit here and have a heart attack?
法兰克，你要跳舞，还是坐在这里等心脏病发作？
Who? Me, dance? I want a heart attack instead.
谁？我跳舞？我宁愿心脏病发作
Don't foam into the Dommie P.
别淹死在酒里了
How about you?
你呢？
What? You want me to dance?
什么？你要我去跳舞？
Yeah, sure. Go on, Tony. You dance.
当然，去啊，东尼，你去跳舞
Go on. Have some fun.
去啊，开心去玩
What do you think of him?
你觉得他怎么样？
I think he's a fucking peasant!
我认为他是一个他妈的农民！
But you get a guy like that on your side,
但你要是让这样的人站在你这边
he breaks his back for you.
他会为你鞠躬尽瘁
-What's your name?   -What?
-你叫什么名字？ -什么？
What's your name? Elvira what?
你叫什么名字？艾薇拉什么？
-Hancock.   -What?
-汉考克  -什么？
-Hancock!  -Hancock?
-汉考克！ -汉考克？
Sounds like a bird. Hancock.
听起来像只鸟
Flying around.
飞来飞去
Where you from?
你是哪里人？
-Baltimore.  -What?
-巴尔的摩  -什么？
-Baltimore!    -Baltimore?
-巴尔的摩！ -巴尔的摩？
-Where's that?   -It doesn't really matter, okay?
-那是哪里？ -那不重要，行吗？
I'm just trying to be friendly.
我只是想表现友善
I don't need another friend,
我不需要朋友
especially one who just got off a banana boat.
特别是刚刚从香蕉船上下来的人
Banana boat?
香蕉船？
Hold it. You got the wrong guy.I don't come off no banana boat.
等等，你搞错了，我不是从香蕉船上下来的
You're thinking of someone else, maybe.
你可能认错人了
Aren't you part of the Cuban crime wave?
你不是古巴罪犯潮里的一员吗？
What you talking crazy for? I'm a political refugee here.
你在说什么疯话？我是政治难民
-So take it easy. Don't talk crazy.   -Sorry.
-放轻松，别说疯话  -抱歉
I didn't know you were so sensitive about your diplomatic status.
我不知道你对自己的外交身分这么敏感
What is your problem, baby?
你哪里有病啊，宝贝？
You're good-looking.
你漂亮
You got a beautiful body, beautiful legs,
身材好，腿又长
a beautiful face, all these guys in love with you.
脸蛋也标致，每个人都拜倒你的裙下
Only you got a look in your eye
可是你的眼神看来
like you haven't been fucked in a year!
好像一整年都没男人碰过你了
Hey, José.
够了
Who, why, when and how I fuck is none of your business, okay?
谁何时在哪里跟我怎么上床都不关你的事，懂吗？
Now you're talking to me, baby.That I like. Keep it coming.
你终于跟我说人话了，宝贝，我喜欢这样，继续啊
Don't call me "baby"! I'm not your baby.
别叫我宝贝！我不是你的宝贝
Not yet, but you gotta give me some time.
还不是，不过你要给我一些时间
Even if I were blind, desperate,
就算我瞎了
starved and begging for it on a desert island,
在一个荒岛上饿到快死也不会要你
you'd be the last thing I'd ever fuck.
怎么轮也轮不到你
That chick he's with...
那个女的…
-Yeah?    -...she likes me.
-怎么？ -她喜欢我
She likes you? How do you know?
她喜欢你？你怎么知道？
I know.
我就是知道
The eyes, chico. They never lie.
眼睛，小子，眼睛不会说谎
-Are you serious?   -Serious? What do you think?
-你说真的？ -真的？你说呢？
That's the boss's lady, okay?
那是老大的女人，懂吗？
-You're gonna get us killed.   -Fuck you, man. The boss's lady.
-你会害死我们  -去你的，老大的女人
That guy's soft.
那家伙是个软脚虾
Look in his face.
看看他那张脸
The booze and the concha tell him what to do.
酒跟女人让他做什么，他就做什么
Don't fucking go crazy on me, okay?
别他妈的跟我胡来，知不知道？
Just remember last year at this time we were in a fucking cage, okay?
你还记得去年这个时候，我们还在他妈的牢里吗？
You remember.
你记得
I'd like to forget that.
我想忘了这件事
-I say be happy with what you got.   -You be happy.
-要知足  -你很知足
-Me, I want what's coming to me.   -What's coming to you?
-我，我要我应得的  -你应得的是什么？
The world, chico,
全世界
and everything in it.
和世上的一切
Oh, man.
老天
THREE MONTHS LATER
3个月后
This is paradise.
这里是天堂
This is paradise, I'm telling you.
这里是天堂，我跟你说
This town's like a great big pussy just waiting to get fucked.
这个镇就像个等人调戏的风骚女人
I should've come here 10 years ago.
我十年前就该来了
I'd have been a millionaire by this time.
那样我现在应该是个百万富豪了
By this time, I'd have had my own boat,
现在我应该有自己的船
my own car, my own golf course.
自己的车，自己的高尔夫球场
You know what I want? I thought of this the other day.
你知道我想要什么吗？我前几天才在想
A line of blue jeans.
一个牛仔裤品牌
With my name written on the back of chicks' asses.
把我的名字写在女人的屁股上
How's that?
怎么样？
That sounds completely crazy to me.
我觉得很疯狂
Look at that. Look.
看、看
You're missing the sights. That's what you're doing.
你错过风景了，你就是这样
We're missing the action.
我们错过好东西了
Want to have some ice cream with my friend and me?
要不要和我们一起去吃冰淇淋？
Get lost, greaseball!
滚开，混球！
-Look at that.    -Ice cream?
-看吧  -冰淇淋？
-That's right.   -You said "ice cream"?
-没错  -你说：“冰淇淋”?
-Girls like ice cream.   -Oh, come on. That won't work.
-女生都爱冰淇淋  -拜托，这点子真烂
You can't do it that way.
你这样不行的
You know how you pick up chicks in this country?
你知道在这个国家要怎么钓马子吗？
-What was that? What you just did?   -That's what you do.
-那是什么？你在干嘛？ -就是这样
-That's disgusting.   -Watch.
-好恶心  -看好
Look at that fucking thing. You look like a lizard.
你看起来像只蜥蜴
Like a bug coming out of your mouth.
好像嘴里还有只虫似的
Figures you wouldn't understand.
就知道你不会懂
But the women in this country, when you do that, they know.
但是这里的女人，你这样做，她们会明白
-They know what?   -They understand. They go crazy.
-明白什么？  -她们懂，她们会为之疯狂
It'll take practice, but you gotta learn.
这需要练习，不过你一定要学
'Cause women love when you suck the pussy.
因为女人喜欢人家舔鲍鱼
Look at that.
看
She's looking at us.
她在看我们
-You think you can do it with her?   -I think I can.
-你觉得能和她上床吗？  -我看没问题
-You want to try it with her?   -Why not?
-你要拿她来试试吗？ -有何不可？
-You gonna watch me?   -I'm looking at you. Go ahead.
-你要看我做吗？  -我在看，去啊
-You won't do it.    -Watch this.
-你不去啊  -看好了
I'm with you, man.
我支持你，兄弟
I'm gonna get her.
我会钓到她
Go ahead, Romeo! Do your thing.
放马过去，罗密欧！
-Just be quiet. Just hang back.   -Romeo!
-小声点，别靠过来  -罗密欧！
You're looking very pretty today.Yes, you. I've been watching you.
你好漂亮，对，就是你，我一直在观察你
You want to see something funny?
你想看好笑的事吗？
Take a look over there. See that man?
看那边，看到那个男的吗？
Watch that guy. I gotta sit down here.
看着那个男的，借我坐一下
I gotta watch my friend.
我要看我的朋友
He gonna stick his tongue out to that girl.
他要对那个女的吐舌头
Oh, look at that.
看
You're sick!
变态！
You see what happened to him?
你看到他的下场了吗？
-If I wasn't a nice guy...   -She's too big for you.
-如果我不是个好人…  -她不适合你
Causing trouble like that, come on.
麻烦大了，走吧
-Bitch! Lesbian!   -What I try to tell you?
-贱女人！贱货！  -我不是跟你说过了？
What I try to tell you?
我不是跟你说过了？
This country, you gotta make the money first.
在这个国家，你要先赚到钱才行
Then when you get the money, you get the power.
有钱就有权
Then when you get the power, then you get the women.
有权就有女人
That's why you gotta make your own moves.
所以你要自己当老大
That's the one I rented.
那个是我租的
No. That's her, man. There she is.
不，她来了，她在那里
About time.
时间也差不多了
Frank got held up at the golf course.
法兰克在高尔夫球场走不开
He told me to pick you up.
他让我来接你
He said he'd meet us at the track later.
他说等会在跑马场和我们会合
He said to bet on Ice Cream in the first, by the way.
他还交代，第一场要买冰淇淋
In that thing? You must be kidding.
坐这东西？你一定是在开玩笑
What you talking about? That's a Cadillac.
你在说什么？那可是凯迪拉克
-I wouldn't be caught dead in that.   -Oh, come on.
-我死也不会上车 -拜托
It's got a few years, but it's a cream puff.
旧是旧了点，但是是奶油色的
It looks like somebody's nightmare.
看起来像恶梦
So, you like this better?
这个好些吗？
Yeah.
嗯
It's like one of them tigers from India.
像印度虎一样
Tigers, huh? Tigers, no?
老虎？老虎才怪？
Crazy guy. Know what he's been doing?
疯子，你知道他都在干嘛吗？
Dragging me to the zoo to look at tigers.
拉我去动物园看老虎
He says he's gonna buy one.
他说要买一只
You do that and you won't have any friends left.
你这样做，所有的朋友都会跑光光
-Not that you have any now.   -You're gonna like that tiger, man.
-虽然你本来就没几个朋友  -你会喜欢那只老虎的
You gonna drive around with a tiger in your passenger seat?
你打算把老虎放在后座，开车到处去？
Maybe. Some lady tiger.
说不定某只母老虎
-How much?   -43,000, fully equipped.
-多少钱？  -四万三，全配备
-That all?   -Machine-gun turrets are extra.
-就这样？  -机关枪要另外加
He's a funny guy. Come here, Manny.
真是个风趣的家伙，过来，曼尼
Bulletproof this, okay?
这里要防弹，知道吗？
And this here and here.
还有这里跟这里
- Okay.  - And the windows.
-可以  -还有窗
-Get me a phone with a scrambler.   -A scrambler.
-还有一支有防窃听的电话  -防窃听器
And a radio with scanners
还有无线电扫描仪
to pick up flying saucers, stuff like that.
好扫描飞碟出没，像这样的东西
Don't forget the fog lights.
别忘了雾灯
Oh. In case I get caught in a swamp. That's a good idea.
以防我被困在沼泽里，好主意
Get out of the way, lady! I'm trying to drive here!
让路，女士！我在开车！
I thought you were taking me to Frank.
我以为你要载我去找法兰克
We got an hour. You hungry?
还有一个小时，你饿吗？
No, but I'm bored.
不饿，但是很无聊
Well, that figures.
我就知道
Check it out, Manny, okay? And pay the guy.
你来搞定，曼尼？付他钱
And you take a taxi. Meet me at the track, okay?
你自己搭出租车，和我在跑马场碰头，可以吗？
-Good doing business with you.   -Mr. Montana.
-很高兴和你做生意  -蒙大拿先生
Oh, God, man!
噢，老天！
I wouldn't buy the car if you didn't like it.
如果你不喜欢这辆车，我就不会买
Planning on driving the girls crazy, aren't you, Tony?
想让女孩为你晕头转向，对吧，东尼？
Oh, yeah. You know who?
你知道是谁吗？
What would Frank say?
法兰克会怎么说？
I like Frank, you know?
我喜欢法兰克，你呢？
Only I like you better.
只是我更喜欢你
-You got some for me?   -Sure.
-分我一点？ -好啊
Okay.
好
Don't get confused, Tony. I don't fuck around with the help.
别搞错，东尼，我不和下人乱搞
You wanna play that way with me, I play with you.
你想和我玩游戏，我就和你玩
Shit.
狗屎
Would you kiss me if I wear the hat?
如果我带帽子，你会亲我吗？
No!
不会！
Playtime is over, okay?
游戏时间结束了，懂吗？
Okay.
好
Mama?
妈妈？
Antonio.
安东尼奥
Long time.
好久不见
No postcards from jail, huh?
在牢里都不写信回来？
Gina.
吉娜
-Tony?   -Look at you.
-东尼？ -看看你
You're beautiful.
你真美
-I didn't...   -Mama, look at those eyes, huh.
-我没…  -妈妈，看她那双眼睛
Look at that. She looks like me.
你看，她跟我好像
You know the last time I saw you, you was like that.
上次我见到你的时候，你才这么大
You looked like a little boy. Now look at you.
像个小男生，现在你看看
I got something for you.
我有东西给你
It's no big deal.
只是个小东西
Oh, Tony!
东尼！
I never thought I'd see you again, you know?
我以为再也见不到你了，你知道吗？
You think they'd keep a guy like me down?
你以为他们能关得住我吗？
Well, no.
才不
-You look so good.   -Look, open that up. Open it.
-你看来很好  -打开来看，打开
-For me?   -I think so.
-给我的？ -应该是
It's nothing much, you know, nothing.
只是个小东西，你知道，不算什么
See what's written on the back?
看看后面写了什么？
On the back? Aw.
后面？
东尼送给吉娜，直到永远
-Always.   -"Always." It's beautiful, Tony!
-直到永远  -“直到永远”，真美，东尼！
Mama is still working in the factory,
妈妈还在工厂工作
and I work part-time in a beauty parlor.
我在美容院打工
I'm doing hair, Tony. Do you remember Hiram Gonzalez?
我是美发师，东尼，你还记得海瑞工萨尔吗？
His father owned that barbershop. It's his place.
那间理发院是他爸爸开的，是他的地方
Plus I go to junior college. Miami Dade.
而且我在读短期大学，在迈阿密戴德
In two more years, I get my cosmetology license.
再两年，我就可以拿到美容师牌照
-Then I'll be making enough money...   -Surprise!
-然后我就会赚够钱…  -惊喜一下！
All that's over, starting today.
全都结束了，从今天开始
Why?
为什么？
My kid sister don't have to work in no beauty parlor, and Mama,
我的小妹妹不需要在美容院做事，我妈也是
she don't have to sew in no factory.
她不需要在工厂做衣服了
Your son made it, Mama.
你儿子办到了，妈
He's a success.
他成功了
That's why I didn't come around before.
这就是为什么我前一阵子都没来
I want you to see what a good boy I've been.
我要你看看我现在有多吃得开
Here's $1,000.
这里是一千块
For you, Mama.
给你的，妈妈
-Who did you kill for this, Antonio?   -Mama.
-这是杀了什么人赚到的，东尼？  -妈
I didn't kill nobody, Mama.
我没杀人，妈
- No?   - No.
-没有？  -没有
What are you doing now?
你现在在做什么？
Banks, or is it still bodegas, you and the others?
你和其它人现在是抢银行，还是小杂货店？
No! Things are different now.
不是！现在不一样了
I'm working with an anti-Castro group.
我和反卡斯特罗集团合作
I'm an organizer now.
我现在负责组织筹划
I get a lot of political contributions.
我做了很多政治贡献
Sure you do.
说得好听
A gun sticking in somebody's face is how.
靠把枪指在别人头上赚钱
You know, all we hear about in the papers
我们在报纸上看得多了
is animals like you and the killings.
都是像你这样的禽兽跟杀人案
It's Cubans like you who are giving a bad name to our people,
就是像你这样的古巴人，把我们人民的名声搞臭了
people who come here, work hard and make a good name for themselves.
那些来这里勤奋工作，为自己建立了好名声的人
People who send their children to school.
那些送孩子们去上学的人
What are you saying? That's your son...
你在说什么？那是你儿子…
Son? I wish I had one.
儿子？我有儿子吗？
-He's a bum.   -No.
-他是痞子  -不
He was a bum then and he's a bum now.
他以前是个痞子，现在也是个痞子
Who do you think you are?
你以为你是谁？
We haven't heard a word from you in five years.
五年来，只字片语都没有
You suddenly show up here, throw some money around
现在突然出现，拿钱砸人
and think you can get my respect.
以为这样我就会看得起你
You think you can buy me with jewelry?
你以为可以用珠宝买通我？
You think you can come into my house with your hotshot clothes
你以为你可以穿名牌衣服到我家
and your jail manners and make fun of us?
用你在牢里学的态度来嘲笑我们？
-You don't know what you're saying.   -That's not the way I am, Antonio!
-你不知道自己在说什么  -我不是哪种人，安东尼奥！
That is not the way I raised Gina to be!
那也不是我教养吉娜的方式！
You are not going to destroy her.
你不准毁了她
I don't need your money.
我不需要你的钱
I work for my living.
我自己会赚钱
I don't want you in this house anymore!
我不要你再出现在我家！
I don't want you around Gina.
我不要你接近吉娜
So come on. Get out!
所以，滚出去！
Okay.
好
Mama...
妈妈…
And take this lousy money with you. It stinks.
把你的脏钱拿走，臭死了
Tony.
东尼
Why do you have to spoil it for everybody, huh?
你为什么非让大家都难过不可？
I'm sorry, Tony.
对不起，东尼
Okay, Mama.
好吧，妈妈
No. Tony, wait a minute!
东尼，等等！
-Don't go, please!   -Gina, stay here!
-别走，拜托！ -吉娜，站住！
-No, Mama.   -He's no good. Gina!
-别这样，妈妈  -他没救了，吉娜！
Tony, wait, please!
东尼，等等，拜托！
I'm sorry. I don't know. Mama, ever since Papa left, she's...
对不起，我不知道自从爸爸走了之后，妈妈她…
Forget Papa. We never had one.
忘了爸爸吧，我们没有爸爸
I know you did some bad things back then.
我知道你在那边做过不好的事
In the Army, I know you got into some trouble.
在军队里，我知道你遇到麻烦
The Communists,
共产党
they're always trying to tell you what to do.
他们总是试图告诉你该怎么做
-Mama doesn't understand that.  -I know.
-妈妈并不了解这些  -我知道
I just... I don't know.
我只是…我也不知道
I just want you to know that I don't care.
我只是想让你知道，我不在乎那些
It doesn't matter to me how long you've been away, five or ten years.
不论你离开多久，五年也好，十年也好，我都不在乎
You're my blood, always.
你是我的至亲，永远都是
I know.
我知道
-Come on. I want you to take this.   -I gotta go back in.
-来吧，我要你拿去  -我必须回去了
-No, Tony. Please.  -You need this.
-别这样，东尼，拜托  -你需要这个
What will I tell her?
我要怎么跟她说？
Take that. You don't tell her anything.
拿去，什么都别跟她说
Don't tell her I gave it to you, but give her some from time to time.
别说是我给你的，但是隔一段时间就拿一些给她
And listen, you go out yourself.
听好，你自己要出去玩
Go ahead. Go out, do some things. Have some fun.
出去找点事做，玩得开心一点
You gotta get some fun out of life.
你一定要享受人生的乐趣
You gonna beat yourself to death at 19?
你不想19岁就过劳死吧？
A pussycat like you? Come here.
像你这么漂亮的女生？过来
-I'll talk to you again.   -Okay.
-我们以后再聊  -好
Put that money away. Don't let her see it.
把钱收好，别被她看到了
I'll talk to her.
我会和她谈谈
-I'll talk to you.  -Okay.
-我们以后再聊  -好
Let's go.
走吧
-She's beautiful. How come you...   -Hey!
-她真漂亮，你怎么… -嘿！
Stay away from her. You hear?
离她远点，听到没？
-She's not for you.   -Okay.
-别打她主意  -知道了
COCHABAMBA, BOLIVIA
玻利维亚 科恰班巴
So, this and my other factory, I can guarantee production
这间工厂加上我的工厂，我可以保证
of 200 kilos refined every month of the year.
每个月生产两百公斤纯古柯碱
The problem is, I have no steady market.
问题是我没有稳定的市场
Basically, what I'm looking for is somebody in the States
基本上我需要的是一个在美国
who can share the risk with me, somebody who can guarantee
可以和我分担风险的人，一个可以保证
to buy from me, say, 150 kilos a month.
每个月跟我买一百五十公斤货的人
Oh, that's a big commitment, Mr. Sosa. Something like that...
这是个很大的承诺，索沙先生，像这样的…
Too bad Frank's not here. You should talk to him.
法兰克不在真是太糟了，你应该和他谈谈
-It would've been nice if he'd come.   -He would like to come,
-如果他能来就好了 -他很想来
but with his trial coming up, it's hard to leave the country.
但是他的案子就快开庭了，不方便出国
-So he sent you instead?   -Something like that.
-所以他派你来？ -差不多
We'll talk at my house, shall we?
我们到我家谈，好吗？
You got good stuff here. Class-A shit.
你的东西不错，上等货色
This Lopez guarantees to buy 150 kilos from me
罗培兹保证每个月跟我买
every month of the year.
一百五十公斤的货
He picks it up here.
接下来就由他搞定
I can sell it to him for as little as
我最便宜可以卖他
7,000 a key. You can't do better than that.
一公斤七千元，不可能再更便宜了
But then we got to take the risk of moving it.
但是我们要承担运送的风险
We'll be cutting out the Colombians. Know what that means?
我们也会踢走哥伦比亚人，你知道这代表什么吗？
That means we have to go to war with them.
这代表我们和他们开战
We cut out the Colombians, we take risks on both sides.
我们踢走哥伦比亚人，我们承担双重风险
Why don't we split the risk?
我们何不平分风险？
You guarantee your delivery, say, as far as Panama,
你保证货会运到巴拿马
we take it from there.
我们从那里接手
Panama is risky. It costs me more.
巴拿马风险太高了，会增加我的成本
Panama I can sell for 13.5 a key.
巴拿马的话，一公斤我要卖一万三千五百元
13.5? What, are you nuts?
一万三千五百元？你疯了吗？
13.5? We still got to take that shit to Florida.
一万三千五百元？我们还得把东西运到佛罗里达
Do you know what that's like these days?
你知道最近是什么状况吗？
You got the Navy everywhere.
到处都是海军
You got frogmen. You got EC2s with the satellite-tracking shit.
有蛙人，还有装了雷达追踪器的军舰
You got the fucking Bell 209 assault choppers up the ass.
还有他妈的攻击直升机在上方飞
We're losing one out of every nine loads.
九批货就有一批被抄到
That's no duckwalk anymore, let me tell you.
事情没那么容易了，我告诉你
Forget about 13.5.
一万三千五百是不可能的
What do you suggest that is reasonable?
那你说多少才合理？
Excuse me. One moment.
抱歉，稍等一下
What the fuck's the matter with you?
你在搞什么鬼？
Are you negotiating for Frank Lopez?
你是在帮法兰克罗培兹谈判吗？
Don't worry about it. Take it easy.
别担心，放轻松
I'm not worried about it. You should worry about it.
我没担心，你才应该担心
If he wants to make a deal, it's up to him, not you.
如果他想谈成生意，他说了算，不是你
We're doing this one deal. That's it.
我们只做这一笔，就一次
Fuck you. How's that?
去你的，你觉得怎样？
-Fuck you.  -Fuck you.
-去你的  -去你的
You need to open your eyes and keep your mouth shut.
你只要张大眼睛，闭上嘴就行了
-That's it. Let it go at that.   -Don't worry about it.
-就这样，别得寸进尺  -别担心
Your head's in the wrong place. You must watch out for yourself.
你头脑用错地方了，你自己要小心
Why not talk to him?
为什么不和他谈？
You think he wants to give you the money?
你以为他会给你钱？
Shut the fuck up.
闭嘴
I'm doing the talking here, not you.
是我在谈判，不是你
You're here to watch my back. Watch my back.
你是来保护我的，来保护我的
Better than your front, let me tell you.
保护得很周到，让我告诉你
That's easier to watch.
只是看很简单
Close your mouth.
闭嘴
I can't wait to see what Frank's gonna react to this one.
我等不及想看法兰克的反应了
Just shut up. I'm doing the talking here.
闭嘴，这里由我负责
-Now where were we?  -Panama.
-我们刚才谈到哪里？ -巴拿马
You're looking for a partner, right?
你是在找合作伙伴，对吧？
Something like that.
差不多
Look, Mr. Sosa, we're getting ahead of ourselves.
听着，索沙先生，我们发展得太快了
I am down on Frank's authority to buy 200 keys, that's it.
法兰克只授权我买两百公斤，就这么多
That's my limit. I got no right.
这是我的极限，我的权力只有这么多
-Nobody got no right to negotiate...  -Let the man finish, okay?
-每个人都有权谈判… -让他说完，好吗？
Let him propose a proposition, then we can talk more.
让他提出条件，然后我们再谈
You got no authority here.
你没有授权
I started you in this business, so shut the fuck up.
我带你入行的，所以闭上你的嘴
-Frank is gonna love it.   -That's up to Frank, not you!
-法兰克会很高兴  -那要看法兰克怎么说，不是你！
I'm sorry about this, Mr. Sosa.
我很抱歉，索沙先生
No, it is all right.
不，没关系
You're right. Maybe you should talk to Frank.
你说的没错，或许你该和法兰克谈
Well, good.
好，很好
I don't think it's something I want to do on an overseas phone.
这种事在国际电话上不方便说
But as soon as I get back to Miami,I will talk to Frank personally.
不过我一回到迈阿密就会亲自跟法兰克说
Good.
很好
My associates can escort you to my chopper
我的手下会带你去我的直升机
to take you to Santa Cruz.
载你去圣塔克鲁斯
I have a jet there. You'll be in Miami in five hours.
那里我有架喷射机，你五个小时内就会回到迈阿密
You'll be back here tomorrow in time for lunch.
你还赶得及明天回来吃午饭
Good.
好
Good talking to you.
很高兴和你谈话
Why not leave your friend here?
何不把你朋友留下？
While you're gone, he can tell me how to run my business.
趁你不在时，他可以和我说说怎么做生意
-I think Frank wants to see him.   -No, that's okay.
-我觉得法兰克会想见他 -不，没关系
You tell Frank I'm keeping this guy on ice for him.
你跟法兰克说我帮他把香槟准备好
I guess so.
我想也是
Let's finish our lunch.
我们继续午饭吧
I have to hand it to you, Mr. Sosa.
我很敬佩你，索沙先生
You got everything a man could want.
一个男人想要的，你全都有了
I like you, Tony. There is no lying in you.
我喜欢你，东尼，你很诚实
Unfortunately, I don't feel the same about the rest of your organization.
不幸，你组织里的其它人却不是
What do you mean by that, Mr. Sosa?
你是什么意思，索沙先生？
I'm talking about Omar Suarez.
我是说奥马尔苏亚雷斯
This garbage was recognized by my associate at lunch
午饭时，这个垃圾被我朋友认了出来
from several years ago in New York.
很多年前在纽约见过他
He was an informer for the police.
他是警方的线人
He put Vito Duval and Nello and Gino Ramos away for life.
他害维特多瓦、尼洛和奇诺拉莫斯被判无期徒刑
So how do I know you're not a chivato, too, Tony?
所以我怎么知道你不是警方的线人，东尼？
Hey, Sosa.
嘿，索沙
Let's get this straight now.
让我们现在就弄清楚
I've never fucked anybody over who didn't have it coming.
我这辈子从来没整过不该整的人
You got that?
你懂吗？
All I have in this world is my balls and my word.
在这世上，我有的就是勇气跟信用
I don't break them for no one, you understand?
我不会为任何人牺牲它们，你懂吗？
That piece of shit up there, I never liked him,
上面那个垃圾，我从来就没喜欢过他
I never trusted him.
我从来就不信任他
For all I know, he had me set up
他设计我
and had my friend Angel Fernandez killed.
害我朋友安吉费南德斯被杀
But that's history. I'm here, he's not.
不过这些都是过去的事了，我还在，而他不在了
You want to go on with me, say it.
你想继续和我做生意，就说一声
You don't, then you make a move.
要是你不想，那就采取行动
I think you speak from the heart, Montana.
我想你说的是真心话，蒙大拿
But I say to myself,
但我跟我自己说
"This Lopez, your boss,
你老大罗培兹
"he had chivatos like that working for him."
“他竟然用那种内奸帮他做事”
His judgment stinks.
他判断力超差
So I think to myself,
所以我在想
"How many other mistakes has this Lopez guy made?
“罗培兹这家伙还犯了哪些错？
"How can I trust his organization? " You tell me, Tony.
“我怎能信任他的组织？"你告诉我，东尼
Frank is smart, you know?
法兰克很聪明，你知道吗？
You can't blame him for that animal.
你不能把那个禽兽算在他头上
It's a crazy business we're in, you know?
我们干的是疯狂的勾当，你知道吧？
That could happen to anyone, even you.
这种事可能发生在任何人身上，包括你
Why don't I go back and talk to Frank
何不让我回去和法兰克说说
and work it out?
安排好细节？
I'll fix things between us.
我会搞定我们之间的事
You got my word on that.
我保证
I think you and me, we can work this thing out,
我相信你和我，我们能解决这件事
we do business together a long time.
我们还要一起做很久的生意
Just remember,
不过要记住
I'll only tell you one time,
我只跟你说一次
don't fuck me, Tony.
别想唬弄我，东尼
Don't you ever try to fuck me.
连想都别想
罗培兹汽车经销商
You what?
你说什么？
You made a deal for fucking $18 million
你谈了一笔一千八百万元的交易
without even checking with me?
竟然没有先问过我？
Are you crazy, Montana? Are you crazy?
你疯了吗，蒙大拿？你疯了吗？
-Cono. Take it easy.   -Cono, my ass!
-放轻松  -轻松个屁！
At 10.5 a key, it's puro.
一公斤一万零五百元，是上等货
You can't lose money. No way.
你不会赔钱的，不可能
We make 75 million on this deal.
这笔交易你会赚七千五百万元
75 million.
七千五百万元
That is serious money.
这可是很大一笔钱
What is Sosa going to do
我拿不出首期的五百万元时
when I don't come up with the first 5 million?
索沙会怎样？
What is he going to do? Will he send me a bill?
他会怎样？寄账单给我吗？
He'll send a hit squad up here! There'll be a war in the street.
他会派杀手过来！会血溅街头
Relax! Take it easy. I'm in tight with Sosa.
放松点！别紧张，我跟索沙很熟
You short a couple of mil, I go on the street for you.
你钱不够，我帮你想办法
I make a couple of moves,
我有门路
a mil here, a mil there, you got it.
这里一百万，那里一百万，没问题的
Okay?
好吗？
You've been making moves on your own?
你一直在干私活？
I got ears, you know. I hear things.
我有耳朵，我会听到风声
What do you hear about Echevierra and the Diaz brothers?
那你有没有听过伊却米亚跟迪亚兄弟？
What about Gomez?
还有高梅兹？
What'll he do when you start moving 2,000 keys...
你开始运两千公斤时，他会怎样…
Fuck Gaspar Gomez and fuck the Diaz brothers!
去他的高梅兹，去他的迪亚兄弟！
Fuck them all!
去他们的！
I'll bury those cockroaches!
我会埋了这些鼠辈！
What they ever do for us?
他们帮过我们吗？
Look, Frank, the time has come.
法兰克，时机到了
We gotta expand.
我们要扩张
The whole operation. Distribution.
整个活动，分销
New York, Chicago, LA.
纽约、芝加哥、洛杉矶
We gotta set our own mark and enforce it.
我们要建立起自己的标准，并且巩固它
We gotta think big now.
我们要把目标放大
Think big.
放大目标
Like your friend Sosa.
像你的朋友索沙
Let me tell you something about that greaseball cocksucker.
让我告诉你那个狡猾的混球
He is a snake, that's what he is.
他是条蛇，那就是他
You turn your back on him, he'll stick it in.
你只要背对着他，他一定会桶你一刀
You don't trust a guy like that.
这种人不能信任
You want me to believe
你要我相信
Omar was a stoolie because Sosa said so?
奥马尔是警方线人，听信索沙的一面之词？
You bought that line?
你信吗？
Maybe I made a mistake sending you down there.
或许我让你去就是一个错误
Maybe you and Sosa know something I don't know.
或许你跟索沙知道一些我不知道的事
Like what?
像是什么？
You tell me, "Like what."
你告诉我“像是什么”
You calling me a liar, Frank?
你是在说我是骗子吗？
That what you're calling me?
你是这样想的吗？
Let's just say I want things to stay the way they are for now.
这么说好了，目前我不想要改变任何事
You stall your deal with Sosa.
你暂缓跟索沙的交易
Stall it?
暂缓？
Okay, boss.
知道了，老大
Come on.
走吧
I am the boss.
我才是老大
-Sure, you're the boss.   -Hey, Tony.
-当然，你才是老大  -嘿，东尼
Remember I told you when you started,
记得你刚入行时，我怎么跟你说的
the guys who last in this business
在这行能撑得久的
are the guys who fly straight,
是有信诺的人
low-key, quiet.
低调，安静
And the guys who want it all,
那些什么都想要的人
chicas, champagne, flash,
酒色财气样样来的
they don't last.
撑不了多久
You finished?
你说完了吗？
Can I go now?
我可以走了吗？
Hi, there.
嗨
You just missed Frank.
法兰克刚走
Too bad.
真不巧
Only I didn't come to see Frank.
不过我不是来找法兰克的
This is not the time or the place, Tony.
时机地点都不对，东尼
-Next time, make an appointment.   -That's okay.
-下次记得先预约  -没关系
I got something important I want to talk to you about.
我有重要的事跟你说
So why don't we have a couple of drinks,
咱们何不喝两杯
act normal,
表现正常点
and just take it easy?
放轻松？
Come on. I like Scotch.
我喜欢威士忌
-Sure. Why not?   -Okay. I won't bite you.
-有何不可吗？ -我不会吃了你
We're all normal here.
这里每个人都很正常
I heard you and Frank aren't working together anymore.
我听说你没在帮法兰克做事了
That's right.
没错
I think it's easier, don't you?
这样比较好，你不觉得吗？
Makes things easier.
事情比较好办
Thank you.
谢谢
Here's to the land of opportunity.
敬这片充满机会的土地
For you, maybe.
对你来说，或许是吧
You like kids?
你喜欢小孩吗？
Kids?
小孩？
Kids. You know, kids. Little kids.
小孩，你知道，小朋友们
Sure. Why not?
当然，有何不可？
As long as there's a nurse.
只要有保姆
Good, 'cause I like kids, too.
很好，因为我也喜欢小孩
I like them. Boys, girls. Don't matter to me.
我喜欢他们，男孩女孩都无所谓
Frank's gonna be back any minute.
法兰克很快就回来了
Come here.
过来
Sit here.
坐这
I want to talk to you. Sit down. I'm not gonna bite you.
我有话跟你说，坐这里，我又不会咬你
Okay, here's the story.
是这样的
I come from the gutter. I know that.
我出身低微，我知道
I got no education, but that's okay.
我没受过教育，但那没关系
I know the street,
我对街上的事很熟
and I'm making all the right connections.
我也建立了很多很好的管道
With the right woman, there's no stopping me.
再加上一个好女人，我会所向无敌
I could go right to the top.
我会上位当老大
Anyway, what I got to tell you is this,
我要跟你说的是
I like you.
我喜欢你
I liked you the first time I laid eyes on you.
第一眼见到你，我就喜欢上你了
I said, "She's a tiger.
我跟自己说“她是只凶猛又性感的老虎
"She'll belong to me."
“她属于我”
Anyway,
总之
I want you to marry me.
我要你嫁给我
I want you to be the mother of my children.
我要你当我孩子的母亲
Me? Marry you?
我？嫁你？
That's right.
没错
What about Frank, Tony?
法兰克呢，东尼？
What will you do about Frank?
你打算怎么处理法兰克？
Frank is not gonna last, okay? He's finished.
法兰克快完了，知道吗？他玩完了
Just think about it, okay?
考虑看看，好吗？
I want you to really think about it.
我希望你认真考虑
I'll go now. Take care.
我要走了，自己小心
All your enemies are gone.
你的敌人都垮了
-Mr. Montana. How are you?   -Hello.
-蒙大拿先生，你好吗？  -哈啰
What the fuck she doing here?
她在他妈的做什么？
Come on, man. She's just dancing. Come on. Take it easy.
没什么，老兄，她只是在跳舞，放松点
-It's just a disco.   -Who's that guy she's with?
-只是跳迪斯科  -跟她一起的是谁？
He's some guy who works for Luco. He's nobody.
他是陆哥的人，只是个小角色
-He's harmless.    -Works for Luco?
-他没杀伤力  -帮陆哥做事的？
Yeah. Forget him.
是，别管他了
Hello, Tony. You remember me?
嘿，东尼，记得我吗？
Bernstein. Mel Bernstein, right?
伯恩斯坦，梅尔伯恩斯坦，对吧？
Chief Detective, Narcotics.
毒品组首席探员
That's right, yeah. I think we should talk.
没错，我觉得我们该谈谈
Talk? What are we going to talk about?
谈谈？我们有什么好谈的？
I ain't killed nobody, not lately.
我又没杀人，至少最近没有
No, not lately.
最近没有
What about ancient history, like Emilio Rebenga?
那以前呢？像是艾米利奥里本嘉？
Or a bunch of whacked-out Indians at the Sun Ray Motel?
或是在阳光旅馆的毒枭？
Whoever's giving you your information
给你情报的人
is taking you for a long ride.
只是在耍你
-Oh, yeah?    -Yeah.
-是吗？  -是
Tony, baby, we gonna talk,
东尼，我们谈谈吧
or am I gonna bust your wiseass spic balls
还是我现在就
here and now?
逮捕你？
Keep your eye on her.
盯着她
-I'll do that.  -Okay.
-我照办  -好
-My office.   -Good.
-我办公室  -好
The word on the street is you're bringing in a lot of yeyo.
街头流言说你进了很多白粉
That means you're not a small-time punk anymore,
这表示你已经不是小角色了
you're public property now.
执法部门盯上你了
Supreme Court says that your privacy can be invaded.
最高法院说不需要顾及你的隐私
Okay. How much?
好吧，要多少？
How much?
多少？
There's an answer to that, too.
这个问题当然也有答案
Here's how much.
这么多
Can you see it?
看到了吗？
-Big number.    -Yeah!
-数字很大  -是啊！
That's on a monthly basis, same thing every month.
这是月费，每个月都是这个数字
You know how this works?
你知道这事怎么运作吗？
No. You tell me.
不知道，你告诉我
We tell you who's moving against you,
我们会通知你谁要对付你
and we shake down who you want shaken down.
我们会帮你处理你要处理掉的人
Let's say that you got a real problem making a collection.
例如你有一笔收不回来的钱
And then we step in for you.
我们会介入
Got eight killers with badges working for me.
有八个穿制服的杀手听命于我
When they hit, it hurts. Same thing works the other way.
他们出手时，效率是很高的，反之亦然
You feed me a bust now and then.
你三不五时爆一些料给我
Some cowboy setting himself up in business.
某个刚开始自立门户的家伙
Small fry, you know?
小鱼，你懂吗？
We like snacks.
我们喜欢蛇
How do I know you're the last cop I'm gonna have to grease?
我怎么知道不会有其它警察找我麻烦？
What about Fort Lauderdale? Metro? DEA?
罗德岱堡警方呢？大都会警方呢？缉毒组呢？
How do I know what rock they're gonna crawl out from under?
我怎么知道还有谁会突然咬我一口？
Well, that's not my business, Tony. We don't cross no lines.
那不关我的事，东尼，我们不会踩过界
You think I want this conversation going any farther than this table?
你觉得我会想让其它人知道我们刚刚谈的事吗？
My guys' got families. They're legitimate cops.
我的人有家庭，他们是正规警员
I don't want to see them embarrassed.
我不想看到他们难堪
If they're embarrassed, they'll suffer.
如果他们难堪，他们会不好受
If they suffer, they'll make you suffer.
如果他们不好受，他们会让你也不好受
You understand what I'm talking about?
你懂我的意思吧？
Thanks for the drink.
谢谢你请我喝酒
By the way,
还有
I got a vacation coming up.
我快要放年假了
I'm gonna take the wife to London, England.
我打算带老婆去英国伦敦
We've never been there.
我们从没去过那里
So throw in a couple of round-trip tickets, first class.
所以，麻烦你准备两张头等舱的来回机票
You gotta smile more, Tony. You gotta enjoy yourself.
你要多笑一点，东尼，要享受人生
Every day above ground is a good day.
活着的每一天都是好日子
-Hello.   -Hello.
-哈啰  -哈啰
Yeah. Now that's the idea.
对，就像这样
Okay, Mel.
再见，梅尔
You think about what I said?
考虑过我的提议吗？
About the kids?
关于小孩的事？
-You know, you are really nuts.   -I'm nuts about you.
-你真是个疯子  -我为你疯狂
Why don't you find your own girl?
你干嘛不找个自己的妞？
-My own girl?    -Yeah.
-自己的妞？  -对
-That's what I'm doing.   -Go do it somewhere else. Get lost.
-我正在这么做啊  -去别的地方做，出去
Maybe I don't hear so good sometimes.
可能是我最近耳背
You won't hear anything if you go on like this.
你再这样，以后可能什么也听不到
Will you do something?
你想怎样？
You're fucking right I'm going to do something!
你他妈的说对了，我就是想怎样！
I'm giving you orders. Blow!
我命令你，滚！
Orders? You giving me orders?
命令？你命令我？
The only thing in this world
这世界上
that gives orders is balls. You got that?
有种才能命令人，你有吗？
Balls.
有种
Let's go.
我们走
Elvira.
艾薇拉
When you gonna learn? Huh?
你什么时候才会学乖？
Looking good, honey. Keep up the bad work.
看来不错，蜜糖，继续保持
-That cocksucker.   -What happened?
-那个王八  -怎么了？
-He put that prick Bernstein on me.   -Who? Lopez did?
-他让那个混蛋伯恩斯坦来找我  -谁？罗培兹？
-How do you know?   -Who else knew about Rebenga? Omar?
-你怎么知道？  -还有谁知道里本嘉？奥马尔？
He's fertilizer.
他死定了
He's letting me know he's got weight on me.
他要我知道他可以给我压力
I'll tell you what, man.
我告诉你
You know our little trip we've been planning to New York?
记不记得我们一直计划去一趟纽约的那件事？
It might be a good time.
或许现在正是时候
Wait. Where you going?
等等，你去哪？
男厕
Welcome to my private room.
欢迎来到我的私人套房
-Your private room.   -This is my private room.
-你的私人套房  -这是我的私人套房
I got a beautiful, nice, white lounge chair for you.
我有张漂亮舒适的长椅让你坐
Gina, you taste so muy bueno.
吉娜，你味道真棒
Tony!
东尼！
-What are you doing?   -Shut up!
-你在干嘛？  -闭嘴！
-What? We wasn't doing nothing!   -Fernando, wait!
-干嘛？我们什么都没做！ -费南度，等等！
Get out!
出去！
Damn you!
去你的！
You think he's cute?
你觉得他可爱吗？
I saw him putting his hand all over your ass.
我看到他对你上下其手
My kid sister in a toilet.
我的小妹妹跟人家进厕所
It's none of your business.
不关你的事
None of my business? The fuck it ain't!
不关我的事？他妈的不关我的事！
-You can't tell me what to do!   -I am telling you!
-你凭什么管我！  -我就是要管你！
Listen to me. Come here.
听好，你给我过来
I catch you here again, I'm gonna wipe you all over the fucking place.
下次再让我看到你在这，我会打得你没处躲
Yeah? Go ahead! Do it now. I want to see it.
是吗？你试试看啊！我等不及了
-I want to see it now, big shot.   -Don't push me.
-打给我看啊，大人物  -别逼我
-I want to see it now!   -Don't push me! Get outta here!
-打给我看啊！  -别逼我！滚出去！
-Go outside.   -You got some nerve, Tony!
-出去  -你无耻，东尼！
You think you can tell me what to do?
你凭什么管我？
You can't tell me what to do. I'm not a baby anymore.
你没有权力管我，我已经不是小孩子了
I'll do what I want to do, see whoever I want to see.
我爱做什么就做什么，爱跟谁一起就跟谁一起
And if I want to fuck them, then I'll fuck them!
爱跟谁上床，就跟谁上床！
Fucking, man! Come on, man.
你干嘛，老兄！别这样，老兄
What the fuck you want? You want something? Huh?
你他妈的想怎样？你有事吗？
No. Don't touch me.
别碰我
-No.   -We've got to get out of here.
-不要  -我们该出去了
Not there. I don't want to go out there.
不要，我不要出去
Another great night here at the Babylon, right?
又是巴比伦的欢乐之夜，对吧？
Okay. All right!
好，很好！
Do another gram, you'll all be babbling on.
再瞌点药就更欢乐了
Is that coke in your bra, or are you just glad to see me?
你胸罩里那粒是摇头丸，还是太兴奋见到我了？
A little bit of hope, I'm sure, yes.
总是有希望的，当然
I'm in a good mood. I was depressed when I got up this morning.
我心情不错，今早起床时本来心情很差的
I had a dry dream, but I'm better now.
做了秋梦，现在好多了
I do Laurel and Hardy in Spanish, too.
我也会用西班牙文演劳莱与哈台
That's the height of culture, I assure you.
这是发扬文化，我跟你保证
But my favorite Cuban of all time has to be Ricky Ricardo.
我最喜欢的古巴人还是瑞奇里卡多
Mr. Babalu himself.
巴巴陆先生
He had the same problem for 10 years.
他这十年的问题都一样
"Lucy, don't come down to the club."
“露西，别去俱乐部”
He's your brother. He loves you. That's why he did it.
他是你哥哥，他爱你才会这样做
All right? He cares about you.
懂吗？他关心你
To him, you're still his little sister.
对他来说，你还是他的小妹妹
That's the problem. He still treats me like I'm a baby.
问题就在这里，他还当我是小孩
I'm 20 years old now.
我已经二十岁了
-I'm not anybody's baby.   -You're so grown-up.
-我不是孩子了  -你已经长大了
Come on, Gina. Put yourself in his place, okay?
别这样，吉娜，站在他的立场想想，好吗？
Right now, you happen to be the best thing in his life,
目前，你是他生命中最好的东西
the only thing that's any good, that's pure.
唯一的好东西，很纯洁的
Of course he doesn't want you mixing with those people,
他当然不希望你和那些人混在一起
growing up to be like him.
变得跟他一样
He has this father thing for you. Feels like he has to protect you.
他当自己是你父亲一样，觉得自己有责任保护你
Protect me against what?
保护我什么？
Against guys like that asshole you were dancing with tonight.
像今晚跟你一起跳舞的混球
I like Fernando. He's a fun guy and he's nice.
我喜欢费南度，他很有趣，人也很好
And he knows how to treat a woman. All right?
他也知道怎么对待女人，你懂吗？
-He knows how to treat a woman?   -Yes.
-他知道怎么对待女人？  -对
By taking her to the toilet to make out?
把人家带到厕所去胡搞？
You've been a great audience. I got a special treat for you.
你是个很好的听众，我有个特别的奖励给你
Here's a guy I found in the jungle
他是我在委内瑞拉的加拉加斯
from Caracas, Venezuela. He's unlike anything you've seen.
丛林里找到的，和你们以前见过的完全不同
Give a warm Babylon welcome to the one and only Octavio!
让我们用热烈欢迎绝无仅有的奥克特维奥！
Look around. Go out with someone who has something on the ball,
四周围看看，和一些成功的人出去玩
-who's going somewhere in life.   -Like who?
-有正常生活的人 -像是谁？
For instance, someone who's got a real job, like a banker.
像是一个有正常工作的人，像是银行员
-Or... Or a doctor, a lawyer...   -What about you?
-或是…或是医生、律师…  -那你呢？
-What are you talking about?    -Why don't you take me out?
-你在说什么？  -你为什么不约我出去？
Are you crazy?
你疯了吗？
I see the way you look at me, Manolo.
我看过你看我的眼神，马诺洛
-Do you think I'm blind? I see.   -Come on.
-你以为我是瞎子吗？我看得见  -拜托
-What?    -Look, Gina,
-怎样？  -看，吉娜
Tony and I are like brothers, all right?
东尼和我就像兄弟一样，知道吗？
You're his kid sister.
你是他妹妹
-So what?    -That's where it ends.
-那又怎样？  -就这样而已
-That's where it stays.   -Are you afraid of Tony, huh?
-就只能是这样   -你怕东尼吗？
-You afraid of Tony's kid sister?   -I'm not afraid of anybody!
-你怕东尼的妹妹吗？  -我谁也不怕！
That's not the point here!
这不是重点！
Oh, fuck.
妈的
It's not for me. Don't look at me.
不是找我的，别看我
-How do you know?   -'Cause I'm not here.
-你怎么知道？  -因为我不在这里
Oh, really? Then where are you?
真的？那你在哪里？
Shit, you're weird.
你这个怪人
-I'm weird?   -Hello?
-我怪吗？  -喂？
-Hello, Miriam?   -Tony!
-蜜莉安？ -东尼！
-Put Manny on, okay?   -Okay. Just a second.
-叫曼尼听电话，好吗？  -等一下
It's Tony.
是东尼
What are you doing, checking up on me?
你在干嘛？在查我吗？
Get your clothes on and meet me
穿好衣服，45分钟之后
in front of Lopez Motors in 45 minutes.
到罗培兹汽车经销店外跟我碰头
-What? What happened?   -Nothing we can't fix.
-什么？怎么了？ -没有我们处理不了的事
All right. I'll be there.
好，我立刻到
You're still on the phone. Let's go.
你还在电话上，动作快
Take it easy, okay?
别紧张，好吗？
I'm leaving now. Fuck.
我现在就走，妈的
-Nick?    -Yeah, Tony.
-尼克？  -是，东尼
This is what I want you to do for me,
我要你帮我做件事
you call Lopez.
打给罗培兹
Call him at his office at 3:00 sharp.
三点整打到他的办公室给他
And you tell him,
你跟他说
"We fucked up, he got away."
“我们搞砸了，他逃走了”
-Okay. Yeah.   -Got it? What are you going to say?
-好  -懂了吗？你该说什么？
"We fucked up. He got away."
“我们搞砸了，他逃走了”
-What time?    -3:00 sharp.
-几点？  -三点整
So when are we gonna make some money on this thing?
这件事我们什么时候可以开始赚到钱？
Six months to start don't mean shit, Larry.
说就说六个月
I'm not a Rockefeller, you know. Not yet, anyway.
我不是洛克菲勒，还没
So you owe me.
你欠我
Listen, go down to the ball game tonight?
今晚去看球赛吗？
I couldn't make it. I got things. I'll tell you about them.
我去不了，有事做，我会跟你说他们的事
You're kidding. What was the score? Three to two?
你开玩笑，比分多少？三比二？
Mel, guess what.
梅尔，猜猜怎么了
My Little League team, the Little Lopezers,
我的小联盟球队，小罗培兹们
they won the division tonight.
今晚赢得分区冠军
That's great. Congratulations.
那很好，恭喜
What'd you do, fix the umpire?
你怎么办到的，贿赂裁判？
Jesus Christ.
老天
Tony, what happened to you?
东尼，你怎么了？
They wanted to spoil my $800 suit.
他们想毁了我八百块一套的西装
Who the fuck did this?
哪个王八蛋干的？
Hitters. I don't know.
杀手，我不知道
Somebody must've brought them in.
一定是有人请来的
I've never seen them before.
我从来没见过他们
Hello, Mel.
哈啰，梅尔
Got an answer to this, too?
你知道是怎么回事吗？
-There always is, Tony.   -I'll bet it was the Diaz brothers.
-总会知道的，东尼  -一定是迪亚兄弟
They got a beef going back to the Sun Ray thing.
他们的人在查阳光旅馆的事
Maybe you're right, you know?
你可能是对的，你知道吗？
Anyway, I'm glad you made it, Tony.
我很高兴你没事，东尼
We'll return the favor for you in spades.
我们会好好报答你
I'll take care of this myself.
我会自己搞定
What is the gun for, Tony?
这枪是干嘛，东尼？
What, this? It's nothing.
这个？没什么
I'm... How do you say? Paranoid.
我…怎么说的？神经过敏
You gonna answer, Frank?
你要接吗，法兰克？
It must be Elvira. She got mad after we left the club.
一定是艾薇拉，我们离开俱乐部后，她大发脾气
I'll tell her you're not here, okay?
要我跟她说你不在吗？
No, it's all right. I'll talk to her.
不用，没关系，我跟她说
Hello.
哈啰
It's all right. I'm gonna be home in an hour. Don't worry.
没关系，我一个小时后回家，别担心
Frank, you're a piece of shit.
法兰克，你是个人渣
-What are you talking about?   -You know what I'm talking about,
-你在说什么？  -你知道我在说什么
you fucking cockroach.
你这个他妈的鼠辈
What are you talking about? Listen to me, huh.
你在说什么？听我说
You know what a chazer is, Frank?
你知道凯泽是什么吗，法兰克？
That's a pig that don't fly straight.
是只不正直的猪
Neither do you, Frank.
你也一样，法兰克
Tony, why the fuck would I hurt you?
东尼，我为什么要害你？
I brought you in.
我带你入行的
So we had a few differences, no big deal.
我们意见不同，那又怎样
I gave you your start. I was the one who believed in you.
我给你机会开始，只有我相信你办得到
I stayed loyal to you.
我对你忠诚
I made what I could on the side, but I never turned on you, Frank!
我有做私活，但我从来没有背叛你，法兰克！
Never!
从来没有！
But you,
而你
a man who ain't got his word is a cockroach.
不守信用，根本是个鼠辈
Mel. Do something, will you?
梅尔，说句话，好吗？
It's your tree, Frank. You're sitting in it.
那是你的问题，法兰克，你自己搞定
All right, Tony. I was the one.
好吧，东尼，是我
Please, give me a second chance.
给我一次机会
Will you do that? Please?
好吗？拜托？
Give me a second chance. I'll give you $10 million.
再给我一次机会，我可以给你一千万元
Okay? $10 million.
好吗？一千万
I got it in a vault over there in Spain, Tony.
我放在西班牙的保险库，东尼
We go over there, we get on a plane, and it's yours.
我们过去，搭飞机过去，钱就都是你的了
Okay? All of it. $10 million.
好吗？全部，一千万
Okay, Tony?
好吗，东尼？
Huh?
Please, Tony?
拜托，东尼？
Elvira? You want Elvira?
艾薇拉？你要艾薇拉？
You can have her. I'll go away. I'm gonna disappear.
她可以跟你，我走，我会消失
You'll never see me again. Please, Tony, I don't want to die.
你再也不会见到我，拜托，东尼，我不想死
I never did nothing to nobody.
我从来没对别人怎样
No, you never did nothing to nobody.
没错，你从来没对别人怎样
You had somebody else do it for you.
你都是叫别人帮你做
Oh, Tony, I'm begging you.
东尼，我求你
-Get up! Get up now!   - Jesus! No! God!
-起来！起来！  -老天！不！老天！
Look. Tony, no! Don't kill me, please.
拜托，东尼！别杀我，拜托
I won't kill you.
我不会杀你
-Oh, Christ, thank you.    -Get off my foot.
-感谢老天  -放开我的脚
-Thank you.   -Manolo, shoot that piece of shit!
-谢谢  -马诺洛，开枪射这混蛋！
No, no!
不，不！
No!
不！
Every dog has his day, huh, Mel?
罪有应得，对吧，梅尔？
I told him
我跟他说过了
it didn't make any sense
根本不合理
clipping you when we had you working for us. He wouldn't listen.
你帮我们做事，为什么要除掉你，但是他不听
He got hot tonight about the broad.
他今晚为了女人的事大发脾气
He fucked up.
他犯下大错
You, too, Mel. You fucked up.
你也是，梅尔，你也错了
Don't go too far, Tony.
别太过分了，东尼
I'm not, Mel. You are.
过分的不是我，梅尔，是你
Fuck. You can't shoot a cop!
干，你敢杀警察！
Whoever says you was one?
谁说你是警察？
Wait a minute!
等等！
You let me go. I'll fix this up.
你放我走，我会搞定这一切
Sure, Mel. Maybe you can handle yourself
好啊，梅尔，或许你可以给自己安排
one of them first-class tickets to the Resurrection.
参加最后审判的头等机票
Fucking punk! Son of a bitch!
混蛋王八蛋！狗娘养的！
-So long, Mel. Have a good trip.   -Fuck you!
-再见了，梅尔，玩得开心点  -去你妈的
-Okay, come on.   -What about Ernie?
-走吧  -恩尼呢？
You want a job, Ernie?
恩尼，要一份工作吗？
-Sure, Tony.   -Okay, then you call me tomorrow.
-当然，东尼  -好，明天打电话给我
Man, you got a job!
老兄，你被雇用了！
Tony! Thanks.
东尼！谢谢
Tony.
东尼
God, what's happened?
老天，怎么回事？
Where's Frank?
法兰克呢？
Where do you think?
你说呢？
Come on. Get your stuff.
把你的东西收一收
You're coming with me.
跟我走
这世界都是你的…
美国三联银行
蒙大拿管理公司
吉娜蒙大拿发廊
So you come to me with some kind of thing. Okay.
你有事来找我，没问题
You propose it, I talk to you.
你提出来，我们谈谈
But we got a problem. I can't pay more.
但是我有个问题，我不能付更多钱
I'm bringing in twice as much as I ever did before.
我现在赚的钱是以前的两倍
We're doing 10 million, 15 million a month. Come on.
我们一个月有一千万，一千五百万再进来
That's serious money.
这是很大一笔钱
You bank boys gotta come down a bit.
你们银行要降低费用
No way.
不可能
-That's crazy. We can't do that.   -Then that's too bad.
-这太超过了，我们办不到   -真糟糕
-What am I gonna do?   -We're not a wholesale operation.
-那我要怎么办？  -我们不是大盘商
We're a legitimate bank. The more cash you give me,
我们是合法的银行，你给我越多现金
the harder it is for me to rinse.
我越难洗
That's a problem. I didn't know.
有个问题，我不懂
The fact is, I can't take any more of your money
情况是我不能再收你的钱
unless I raise the rates on you.
除非我加你手续费
-You gonna raise the...    -I gotta do it.
-你要加…  -非加不可
The IRS is coming...
国税局有动作了…
Don't give me that shit! Let's talk.
少跟我说那些废话！我们谈谈
I'm talking.
谈谈吧
I go low, you go high. I know the game.
我要降，你要加，我知道游戏规则
-This is business talk.   -Let me explain something.
-商业讨论嘛  -让我解释一下
The IRS is coming down heavy on South Florida.
国税局打算严查南佛罗里达
There was a TIME magazine story that didn't help.
《时代》杂志上的一篇报导煽风点火
There's a recession.
现在经济衰退
I got stockholders I got to be responsible for.
我有股东，我要跟他们交代
-I got to do it, Tony.   -You'll learn from him.
-我们非加不可，东尼  -你要跟他学
I got to go 10% on the first 12 million in denominations of 20.
首一千两百万元里面，二十元钞票收百分之十
I'll go 8% on your $10 bills,
十元钞票收百分之八
6% on your fives.
五元钞票收百分之六
-We'll go somewhere else.    -That's it.
-我们会去别家  -够了
-There's no place else to go.   -Fuck you, man! Fuck you!
-没有其它家了  -去你妈的！
I'll fly the cash myself to the Bahamas.
我自己把钱运去巴哈马
Once, maybe. Then what?
一次，或许可以，之后呢？
You'll trust some monkey in a Bahamian bank
你放心把辛苦赚来的两千万元
with 20 million of your hard-earned dollars?
交给巴哈马银行里的笨蛋吗？
Come on, Tony. Don't be a schmuck.
拜托，东尼，别傻了
Who else can you trust?
你还能信任谁？
That's why you pay us so much. You trust us.
所以你会付我们这么多钱，你信任我们
Did you hear that guy?
你听到他说什么吗？
You got to listen to him. You'll learn something.
你该听听他说的话，你会学到东西
Stay with us.
继续待在我们这
You're a well-liked customer. You're in good hands with us.
你是我们尊贵的顾客，我们会好好招呼你
-And I got to run.   -I'm safe but poor.
-我必须走了  -我很安全可是很穷
-How's married life treating you?   -Better than you are.
-新婚生活如何？ -比你的好
Say hello to the princess for me. She's beautiful.
帮我和尊夫人打招呼，她很美丽
-I'll see you. Take care.   -You, too.
-再见  -再见
That prick!
王八蛋！
Fucking WASP whore.
他妈的白烂
Talking to me like I'm some maricón who came over on a boat.
一副我是基佬船民似的
I tell you what. We don't need that smiling motherfucker.
我告诉你，我们不需要这个笑脸王八
We should talk to this Jewish guy, Seidelbaum, okay?
我们应该跟那个犹太人希多本谈谈，好吗？
He's got his own exchange. He charges 4% at the most.
他有自己的兑换所，他最多收百分之四
And he's connected.
他关系很好
Fuck them. Mob guys. Guineas.
去他们的小意大利黑手党
I don't trust them.
我不信任他们
Did you sweep the house this month? The cars?
你这个月清过房子了吗？车子呢？
Yeah, I told you about it. The $5,000?
有啊，我跟你说过了，五千块那笔数？
-Look at that.   -What?
-你看  -什么？
That cable truck there.
那辆有线电视的车
Since when does it take three days to rig a cable?
从什么时候开始装个电视线要三天？
What? You been watching it for three days?
什么？你已经盯它三天？
The thing has been there for three days.
那东西已经在那里停了三天
What am I gonna do, not look at it?
你要我怎么做，不去看它吗？
-What, you think it's cops, right?   -I don't know.
-你觉得是警察，对不对？ -我哪知道
Could be the Diaz brothers, coming to get me.
说不定是迪亚兄弟来找我麻烦
-Maybe. I'll check it out, okay?   -You check it out.
-说不定，我会去查查，好吗？  -你去查查看
Then we're gonna blow that fucking truck back to Colombia!
然后我们就把那辆他妈的货车炸回哥伦比亚去
Come on. We're not the only dopers living on the block.
拜托，这一带又不是只有我们贩毒
Okay? Remember that.
是吗？记住了
That truck could be anybody and anything.
那辆货车可能是任何人的
It could be a cable company...
说不定是有线电视台…
You know something? You got some fucking attitude.
你知道吗？你的态度真他妈差
For someone who's in charge of my security...
你负责我的安全…
Here are the keys to the front door.
这是前门的钥匙
Go down there. Give them the keys!
拿去，把钥匙给他们！
I'm just trying to say something.
我只是想告诉你
You're spending a lot of money on this counter-surveillance.
你花太多钱在反监视系统上
I don't give a fuck.
我不管
It's 12% of our adjusted gross.
占我们收入的一成二
12% isn't peanuts.
一成二不是小数目
I don't give a fuck!
我才不管！
It makes me sleep good at night. That's what counts.
让我晚上能睡得好才是重点
-Okay? You worry about it.   -I am worried about it.
-好吗？交给你来担心  -交给我来担心
I'm telling you. We're getting sloppy.
我告诉你，我们越来越大意了
Our thinking, our fucking attitude, you know?
我们的想法，我们的态度，知道吗？
We're not fucking hungry anymore.
我们他妈的肚子不饿了
Miami's changing. You can see it everywhere.
迈阿密在转变，你随处都看得到
New construction. New jobs.
新建筑，新工作机会
Growth that's financed by Florida Security Trust.
经由佛罗里达安全信托融资而来的成长
We've put your money to work for 75 years,
我们有75年的经验为您规划财务
building a more prosperous Miami.
建设更加繁荣的迈阿密
Count on us being here tomorrow.
您值得信赖的明天
That's because for 75 years, you been fucking everybody.
那是因为你他妈的骗了大家75年
Somebody should do something about those whores.
有人应该出手治治这些贱货
I mean, charging me 10 points on my money.
跟我收一成的费用
They're getting away with it. Fuck, there's no laws anymore.
他们会付出代价的，妈的，简直没王法了
-Forget it.    Anything goes.
-算了吧  -怎样都好
They been around 1,000 years. They got all the angles figured out.
他们已经存在几千年了，连天使都收买了
You know what capitalism is? Getting fucked.
你知道资本主义是什么吗？被他妈的恶整
True capitalist if ever I met one.
我还没遇过真正的资本主义者
Did you hear that?
你有听到吗？
How would you know, bubblehead?
你怎么知道，小笨蛋？
You ever do nothing besides get your hair fixed
你整天除了弄头发跟化妆
and powder your nose?
还做过什么事？
Look at you. You do too much of that shit.
看看你，你吸太多粉了
Nothing exceeds like excess.
没什么比过量更棒的了
-You should know that, Tony.   -I should know what?
-你该知道的，东尼  -我该知道什么？
What should I know?
我该知道什么？
Why do you have to talk to me like that all the time,
你为什么总是那样跟我说话
-like I got to know something?   -Let me talk to you.
-好像我该知道什么似的？  -我有话跟你说
-Listen.    -What time is it?
-听好  -现在几点？
This Seidelbaum...
希多本…
6:55.
六点五十五分
-Okay.   -I met with this guy Seidelbaum...
-好  -我遇到一个叫希多本的家伙…
The drug-related violence that's plagued South Florida...
与毒品有关的暴力行为充斥南佛罗里达…
He's good for a laugh, this guy.
这家伙很搞笑
With a small law-enforcement budget, how can you put a dent
这么少的维安经费，你如何打击
on an estimated $100-billion-a-year business?
一个产值高达一千亿元的行业？
It seems at times all you can do
目前看来，你只能够
is put your finger in the dike and pray.
用手指挡住水坝缺口，祈祷不会溃堤
Put your fingers in a dyke?
用手指挡住水坝缺口？
The only place you can get your fingers
你能放手指的地方
is in some dyke.
只有水坝啊
...Not by outlawing the substances, but by legalizing and taxing them.
不是让毒品非法，而是将毒品合法化并课税
These voices say that will drive out the organized crime element.
有人认为这样会让组织犯罪退出
I am not one of those voices.
我不同意这个观点
I know that. But you know why?
我知道，但你知道为什么吗？
'Cause you got your head up your culo, that's why.
因为你的头接在屁股上，那就是为什么
That fucking guy, he never tells the truth.
那个混蛋家伙，他从没说过真话
...Splendor of our city at its best.
我们华丽的城市
It's those guys, man!
就是这些家伙！
It's the fucking bankers, the politicians,
那些他妈的银行家跟政客
they're the ones that wanna make coke illegal
是他们想让古柯碱非法
so they can make the fucking money and then get the fucking votes!
这样他们不但能从中赚一笔，还能赢得选票！
They fighting the bad guys. They're the bad guys!
他们打击坏人，他们才是坏人！
They fuck anything and anyone.
他们他妈的什么人什么事都搞
Can't you stop saying "fuck" all the time?
你能不能不要一直说脏话？
Can't you stop talking about money? It's boring, Tony.
可不可以不要一直谈钱？那很无聊，东尼
Where's this coming from? Boring? What's boring?
这是怎么回事？无聊？哪里无聊了？
You're boring. Oh.
你很无聊
"Money. " That's all I hear in this house.
“钱”我在这房子里只听得到这个字
Look at these pelicans fly. Come on, pelicans!
看那些鹈鹕在飞，飞啊，鹈鹕！
-Here it is.   -Frank never talked about money.
-来了  -法兰克从来不谈钱
That's 'cause he was so smart.
因为他很聪明
You know what you're becoming?
你知道你变成什么样吗？
You're an immigrant spic millionaire who can't stop talking...
你是小西班牙移民富豪，满口只有钱…
Who the fuck you calling a "spic ," you white piece of bread?
你叫谁“小西班牙”，你这片白面包？
Get out of the way of the TV!
别挡着电视！
Dig a hole in the garden, bury it, and forget about it.
去花园挖个洞，把钱埋起来，然后忘了它吧
I work hard for this! I want you to know that.
我努力赚来的！我要你知道
Somebody should've given it to you. You would've been a nicer person.
有人应该送你钱，你人这么好
Know what your problem is, pussycat?
你知道你的问题在哪里吗，亲爱的？
What is my problem?
我有什么问题？
You got nothing to do with your life.
你的生活太无趣了
Why don't you get a job or something?
你何不去找份工作之类的？
Do something. Be a nurse.
随便做什么都好，当护士吧
Work with blind kids, lepers. That kind of thing.
照顾盲眼小孩跟麻疯病患者那种
Anything beats lying around all day waiting for me to fuck you!
做什么都好过，整天等着你来睡我！
Don't toot your horn, honey. You're not that good.
别太自大了，亲爱的，你没那么厉害
No? Frank was better?
没有？法兰克比较厉害吗？
You're an asshole!
你是个王八蛋！
Where you going? Come here!
你去哪？回来！
Elvie!
艾薇！
I was kidding!
我开玩笑的！
I was only kidding!
我只是开玩笑！
I guess sometimes married life is not all it's cracked up to be.
我猜有时婚姻生活并不像人家说的那么好
-Where you going?   -I got a date.
-你去哪里？  -我有约会
-You got a date? Come here.    -Yeah.
-你有约会？过来  -嗯
-What?   -This Seidelbaum thing.
-什么事？  -希多本那件事
Yeah, it's all set up.
嗯，都安排好了
Yeah, well, you forget it.
好，忘了这件事
Stay out of it. I'll take care of it.
别管了，我来搞定
Stay out of it? It's my deal. I set it up.
别管？那是我的交易，我安排的
You're not a negotiator, Manny, you know that.
你不是个谈判家，曼尼，你知道的
You like the ladies more than the money.
你喜欢妞儿多过喜欢钱
That's your problem.
那就是你的问题
What the fuck are you talking about? I'm your partner, okay?
你他妈的在说什么？我是你的合伙人耶？
If you don't trust me with that kind of thing,
如果你连这都不信任我
who're you gonna trust?
你还能信任谁？
Junior partner.
小股东
Bullshit, man.
狗屎
Don't talk to me about trust, I don't like it.
别跟我说信任，我不喜欢
You should listen to your wife. She's right.
你该听你老婆的，她说得对
You are an asshole, man!
你是个王八蛋！
Come here. Give me a kiss. Come here.
过来，亲一个，过来
Fuck you, man!
去你的！
Who put this thing together? Me! That's who!
是谁打下这一切的？我！是我！
Who do I trust? Me!
我信任谁？我！
Fuck him. "Trust."
去他的，“信任”
Asshole. Fuck called me an asshole.
王八蛋，竟敢叫我王八蛋
I need that shit.
我不需要那些狗屎
I don't need him.
我不需要他
I don't need her. Fuck them. I don't need nobody.
我不需要她，去他们的，我谁也不需要
Back then I worked in pictures down in Colombia.
以前我在哥伦比亚拍电影的
I was in that movie Burn. You ever see it?
我有演《燃烧》那部电影，你看过吗？
You saw me with Marlon Brando? You know, we're good friends.
你有看到我跟马龙白兰度一起吗？你知道，我们是好朋友
-I was his driver.   -No shit?
-我是他的司机  -真的？
-Brando.   -They shot it there. Cartagena.
-白兰度  -他们在卡塔赫纳拍的
Gillo Pontecorvo. He was the director.
杰罗庞泰科法是导演
Italian guy.
意大利人
-Tell me about him.   -I also know Paul Newman.
-告诉我他的事  -我也认识保罗纽曼
-I worked with him in Tucson.   -No kidding?
-我和他在图森一起工作过  -没开玩笑？
Do you know Benny Alvarez?
你认识班尼奥华尔兹吗？
In Tucson. Benny Alvarez?
在图森，班尼奥华尔兹？
-Subtotal.   -No?
-总计  -不认识？
He's a nice guy.
他是个好人
$283, 107.65.
28万3107元6毛5分
You want a company check here?
你要开公司支票吗？
I got 284.6.
我的纪录是28万4600元
That's just not possible. The machine don't make mistakes.
不可能，机器不会弄错
-Let's count it again.   -No. Come on.
-再算一次  -不用了，算了
Business is business. Come on. You're talking $1,500 here.
生意归生意，这里差了一千五百元
Okay, you keep the change. Okay? I don't give a shit.
好吧，零钱你留着，好吗？我无所谓
-I'll count it again for you.   -No, come on.
-我会再帮你算一次  -不用了
This check here, where does this check go?
这张支票要写给谁？
-Montana Realty Company.   -Montana what?
-蒙大拿地产公司  -蒙大拿什么？
Montana Realty Company.
蒙大拿地产公司
-That's 284.   -284,600.
-共28万4000元  -28万4600元
How come you don't know Benny Alvarez?
你怎么会不认识班尼奥华尔兹？
-Me and Benny have lunch together.   -He probably knows me.
-我跟班尼吃过午饭  -他可能认识我
You ask him.
你问他
We're up to what?
现在是多少了？
Seven checks. $1,325,623.
七张支票，132万5623元
200,000 more.
还有20万
-We ought to take a leak.   -Freeze!
-我要去小号  -不准动！
Get your hands up!
把手举起来！
Go against the wall, turn around.
靠墙上，转身
You're not kidding.
你玩真的
You're under arrest for violation of the RICO Statute.
你被以反诈骗腐败组织集团犯罪法逮捕
You have the right to remain silent.
你有权保持沉默
Anything you say can and will be taken against you.
你所说的话将被当作呈堂证供
-How do I know you guys are cops?   -What's that say, asshole?
-我怎么知道你们是不是警察？ -你说什么，王八蛋？
That's pretty good, man. Where'd you get that?
这东西不错，你哪里拿的？
You call yourself a Cuban? You make a real Cuban throw up!
你自称是古巴人？你让真正的古巴人蒙羞！
Call your dog off me, Seidelbaum.
叫你的狗放开我，希多本
-I want to call my lawyer.   -Lot of good he's gonna do you.
-我要联络我的律师  -他帮不上你的
You see that eye there in the clock?
你看到钟里面有个镜头吗？
Say, "Hi, honey."
打个招呼吧
That's pretty cute. Look at that.
真可爱，你看看
You jerk off in front of us, Seidelbaum?
希多本，你在我们面前打手枪？
I was supposed to meet this chick at 3:00.
我本来三点约了个妞
You're a fucking pain in the ass.
你真惹人厌
All right, Benny, kill it.
好了，班尼，关掉吧
You understand the rights I've given you?
你了解我给你的权利吗？
I know all that bullshit, Seidelbaum!
我很了解这些狗屁倒灶的事，希多本！
Save your breath.
你省省吧
You got nothing on me. You know it. I know it.
你没证据可以抓我，你知道，我也知道
I'm changing dollar bills, that's all.
我只是在换钱而已
You want to waste my time? Okay. I call my lawyer.
你要浪费我的时闲？好，我叫我律师来
He's the best lawyer in Miami. He's such a good lawyer
他是迈阿密最厉害的律师，他厉害到
that by tomorrow morning, you gonna be working in Alaska.
明天早上你就会被调去阿拉斯加
So dress warm.
记得穿暖一点
毒枭以五百万元天价交保
Give me a check for 100 grand, plus 300 in cash.
给我一张十万元的支票跟三十万元现金
I guarantee you walk on the conspiracy charge.
我保证你的阴谋罪会被撒销
They're gonna come back at us on a tax evasion,
他们会再告你逃税
and they'll get it.
而且告得成
So, what am I looking at here?
会判多久？
Five years. You'll be out in three.
五年，不过三年就可以出来了
Maybe less, if I can make a deal.
或者更短，如果我能达成协议
Three fucking years!
他妈的三年！
For what?
为了什么？
Washing money? The fucking country was built on washed money.
洗钱？这个他妈的国家就是靠洗钱起家的
Can't be that bad.
没那么糟
-It's not like Cuba.   -What the fuck you talking?
-又不像古巴  -你在他妈的说什么？
-The jails are like hotels.   -You kidding me or what?
-这里的监狱像旅馆一样  -你是在说笑吗？
-You fucking high or what?   -I'll delay the trial.
-你药瞌多了吗？  -我会延后审讯
A year and a half, two years. You won't even start...
一年半，两年，你甚至不必…
Fuck you, man!
去你的！
I'm not going back in any cage, okay?
我绝不会再进牢里，懂吗？
No way. I been there.
绝不，我去过
Okay, look.
好
I give you $400,000 more. Okay, now that's $800,000.
我再给你四十万元，一共八十万元
With that kind of money, you can buy the Supreme Court.
这么多钱，你可以把最高法院也买下来
Tony, the law has to prove beyond a reasonable doubt.
东尼，法律必须能证明超越合理的怀疑
I'm an expert at raising that doubt. But when you got 1.3 million
我是提出质疑的高手，但是你有一百三十万元
undeclared staring into a videotape camera,
没报税的钱，被录像机录下来
honey baby, it's hard to convince a jury you found it in a taxicab.
要说服陪审团你是在出租车上捡到，难度很高
I'm so glad you could come on such short notice.
我很高兴你这么快就赶来
I really appreciate it.
真的很谢谢你
-It's okay.    -How's Elvira?
-没问题  -艾薇拉还好吗？
-Oh, great. How's your wife?   -Three more months.
-很好，你太太呢？  -还有三个月就生了
-Oh, yeah? Congratulations.   -How about you?
-是吗？恭喜你  -你呢？
When you gonna have another Tony to take your place?
什么时候生个小东呢？
-I'm working on it.   -You have to work harder. Come.
-还在努力  -你要加把劲
I want you to meet some of my friends.
我介绍几个朋友给你认识
This is Pedro Quinn,
这是佩特洛坤
chairman of the Andes Sugar Corporation.
安第斯糖业公司的主席
-Pleasure meeting you.   -Nice to meet you.
-很高兴认识你  -很高兴认识你
General Edward Strasser, Commander of the First Army Corps.
爱德华史崔塞将军，第一军团指挥官
Pleasure.
幸会
This is Ariel Bleyer,
这是艾瑞尔布莱尔
with the Ministry of the Interior. Tony Montana.
是内政部的人，东尼蒙大拿
And here is our friend Charles Goodson from Washington.
这是我们的朋友，来自华盛顿的查尔斯古森
-Nice to meet you.   -How do you do, Mr. Montana?
-很高兴认识你  -你好，蒙大拿先生
Sit here, Tony.
坐这，东尼
Gentlemen.
各位先生
I would like to discuss something
我想讨论一些
that is of interest to all of us here.
在座各位都感兴趣的事
You have a problem, Tony.
东尼，你有个问题
We have a problem.
我们也有个问题
I think together we can solve all our problems.
我想合作的话，我们的问题都能获得解决
We all know you have tax troubles in your country
我们都知道你在你的国家有些税务上的麻烦
and that you may have to do a little time.
你可能要坐一阵子牢
We have friends in Washington
我们在华盛顿有朋友
that assure us these troubles can be taken care of.
能保证将这些麻烦处理掉
You may have to pay some back taxes, a big fine,
你可能要补税，罚一大笔钱
but there will be no prison.
但是不用坐牢
Okay.
好
So what's your problem, Alex?
所以你的问题是什么，亚历克斯？
I'll show you my problem.
我让你看看我的问题
I've heard about financial support your government receives
我听说你的政府接受玻利维亚毒品业的
from the drug industry in Bolivia.
金钱援助
Well, the irony of this is that this money,
讽刺的是这笔钱
which is in the billions,
数十亿的钱
is coming from your country.
是来自你的国家
You are the major purchaser of our national product,
你们是我国古柯碱产业
which is cocaine.
最大的客户
On one hand, you're saying the U. S. Government
一方面，你说美国政府
is spending millions to eliminate the flow of drugs onto our streets.
花费数百万遏止毒品流入我们的街头
At the same time,
但同时
we are doing business with the same government
和我们做生意的同一个政府
that is flooding our streets with cocaine.
让古柯碱充斥在我们的街头
Let me show you a few of the other characters
让我再跟你说说几个
that are involved in this tragic comedy.
牵涉在这宗悲喜剧里的人
My organization just recently traced a large purchase by this man.
我的组织最近查到这个人买了一大批货
This charming face here belongs to General Cucombre.
这个人是古坎伯将军
He is the Minister of the Defense of Bolivia, my country.
他是我的国家玻利维亚的国防部长
And General Cucombre just a couple months ago
古坎伯将军几个月前
bought a $12 million villa on Lake Lucerne in Switzerland.
在瑞士卢塞恩湖买了一栋一千两百万元的别墅
Now, if Cucombre is supposed to be the Bolivian Defense Minister,
如果古坎伯是玻利维亚的国防部长
what is he doing living in Switzerland?
为什么他会住在瑞士？
Guarding cash registers?
看钱吗？
This man here, Alejandro Sosa, a very interesting character.
这个人是亚历山大索沙，很有趣的一个人
He's a wealthy landowner,
他是个大地主
educated in England, very good family.
在英国受教育，出身良好家庭
But this man is the business brain and drug overlord
但他是一个跨安第斯贩毒王国的
of an empire that stretches across the Andes.
贩毒王国的主脑
He's not your ordinary drug dealer.
他不是一般的毒枭
Well, discussing it openly...
公开来说…
He's scheduled for 60 Minutes next.
他接下来会上《六十分钟》节目
He is going on French, British, Italian, Japanese television.
他还会上法国、英国、意大利、日本电视
People everywhere are starting to listen to him.
全世界的人都开始听信他
It's embarrassing, Tony.
这很难堪，东尼
That is our problem.
这就是我们的问题
You remember Alberto, don't you?
你记得艾伯特吧？
How could I forget him?
我怎么忘得了？
Alberto is an expert in the disposal business.
艾伯特是处理挡路者的专家
He's going to help us fix our problem.
他会帮我们解决我们的问题
But he doesn't speak English.
但是他不会说英文
He doesn't know his way around the States too well.
他在美国人生地不熟
He needs a little help.
他需要一些协助
Is that a problem, Tony?
这是个问题吗，东尼？
No problem.
没问题
Good.
好
So what's the big mystery with the Bolivian situation?
所以玻利维亚那边有什么大秘密？
You gonna tell me what happened with Sosa, or what?
你不告诉我索沙是怎么回事吗？
A lot of bullshit, that's what happened.
全是废话，就是这样
Politics.
政治
I want you to stay down here for a while.
我要你在这里待一阵子
Run things for me.
帮我打点事情
I gotta go to New York next week.
我下星期要去纽约
Fuck this, man.
妈的
I don't like it, man. I don't like this at all.
我不喜欢，我一点都不喜欢
You don't like it?
你不喜欢？
You got me into this mess in the first place.
是你害我惹上这个麻烦的
With that fucking Seidelbaum, that right?
跟他妈的希多本，知道吗？
With Seidelbaum?
跟希多本？
What does Seidelbaum have to do with Sosa?
希多本跟索沙有什么关联？
How do you connect those two?
两者有何关联？
Why don't you eat your food? What's wrong with it?
你怎么不吃东西？有什么问题？
I'm not hungry.
我不饿
-You're not hungry?   -Do you even know about the trial?
-你不饿？ -你知道开庭的事吗？
-What did you order it for, then?   -I lost my appetite.
-那你干嘛点？ -我没胃口
Do you even know that Sheffield said he can get you a postponement?
你知道雪费德说可以帮你延期吗？
Is this it? That's what it's all about?
是吗？是这样吗？
Eating, drinking,
吃，喝
fucking, sucking...
干，吹…
-Come on, man.    -Snorting?
-好了，老兄  -吸？
Then what?
然后呢？
Tell me. Then what?
告诉我，然后呢？
You're 50. You got a bag for a belly.
你五十岁了，有大肚腩
You got tits, you need a bra.
有奶子，要穿胸罩
They got hair on them.
上面还有胸毛
You got a liver, and they got spots on it
你有个穿了孔的肝
and you're eating this fucking shit
你吃这种垃圾
and you're looking like these rich fucking mummies in here.
你看起来就像个有钱的木乃伊
Come on. It's not so bad. It could be worse.
好了，没那么糟，没有坏到不行的程度
-Is this what it's all about?   -Forget it.
-就是为了这些吗？  -算了
This what I work for? Tell me.
我这么辛苦为了什么？告诉我
Look at that.
看看那
A junkie.
毒虫
I got a fucking junkie for a wife. She don't eat nothing.
我老婆是毒虫，她不吃东西
Sleeps all day with them black shades on.
整天睡觉，还戴太阳眼镜
-Wakes up with a Quaalude...   -Don't pick on her, man.
-吃安眠药…  -别针对她，老兄
...And who won't fuck me 'cause she's in a coma.
不肯跟我上床，因为她已经昏迷了
I can't even have a kid with her.
我跟她连小孩都生不出来
Her womb is so polluted,
她的子宫脏透了
I can't even have a fucking little baby with her!
我甚至他妈的不能跟她有孩子！
You son of a bitch!
你这狗娘养的！
You fuck!
去你的！
-You shouldn't talk like that.   -How dare you talk to me like that!
-你不该这么说  -你凭什么这么跟我说话！
What makes you so much better than me?
你以为自己比我好到哪里去？
-What do you do?   -Don't worry.
-你在干什么？  -没事
You deal drugs and you kill people. Oh, that's wonderful, Tony.
你贩毒又杀人，真厉害，东尼
Real contribution to human history.
对人类历史真有贡献
-Go ahead. Tell everybody.   -You want a kid?
-大声说啊，让大家都知道  -你想要小孩？
Tell the world.
让全世界都知道
What kind of a father would you make?
你会是什么样的父亲？
Gonna drive him to school in the mornings?
一早载他去上学？
Are you even gonna be alive by the time the kid goes to school?
谁知道你能不能活到看小孩上学？
-You don't know how to be a husband!   -Sit down before I...
-你不懂如何当个丈夫！  -坐下，否则…
Do we ever go anywhere without having 600 thugs
我们有没有试过哪次出门时
hanging around all the time?
身边没有一堆保镖？
I have Nick "The Pig" as a friend.
我跟“小猪”尼克是朋友
What kind of life is that?
这是什么样的生活？
Can't you see
你看不出来
what we're becoming, Tony? We're losers.
我们变成什么样吗，东尼？我们是失败者
We're not winners, we're losers.
我们不是赢家，是输家
-Go home. You're stoned.   -I'm not stoned, you're stoned.
-回家，你吸太多毒了  -我没有，是你
-Get her out of here.   -Come on.
-带她离开这里  -走吧
I'm not going home with you.
我不要和你回家
I'm not going home with anybody.
我不要跟任何人回家
I'm going home alone.
我自己会回去
I'm leaving you.
我要离开你
I don't need this shit anymore.
我再也不要这些垃圾
Okay, but I'll walk you out. I'll take her home in a cab.
我送你出去，我会跟她坐出租车回家
Let her go.
让她走
Another Quaalude, she gonna love me again.
再吃一颗安眠药，她就会再次爱上我
What're you looking at?
你看什么看？
You're all a bunch of fucking assholes.
你们全是王八蛋
You know why?
知道为什么吗？
You don't have the guts to be what you want to be.
你们没胆做想做的事
You need people like me.
你们需要像我这样的人
You need people like me
so you can point your fucking fingers
这样你们才可以指指点点的说
and say, "That's the bad guy."
“那是个坏人”
So, what does that make you?
所以你们是什么？
Good?
好人？
You're not good.
你们才不是好人
You just know how to hide,
你们只是知道怎么掩饰
how to lie.
怎么说谎
Me, I don't have that problem.
我没有这种问题
Me, I always tell the truth.
我永远说真话
Even when I lie.
就算是我说谎的时候
So say good night to the bad guy!
所以跟坏蛋说晚安吧！
Come on.
快点
The last time you gonna see a bad guy like this again,
这是你最后一次看到像这样的坏蛋
let me tell you.
我告诉你
Come on. Make way for the bad guy.
来吧，让路给坏蛋
There's a bad guy coming through!
坏蛋来了！
Better get out of his way!
最好别挡着他！
NEW YORK CITY
纽约市
No. You tell Sheffield to keep his nose out of it.
不，你跟雪费德说别插手
There's gonna be no trial. I got it all under control now.
不会开庭了，我都打点好了
Just tell him to stay out of it!
告诉他别管就是了！
Okay, what about Elvira? Did she call?
艾薇拉呢？她有打电话来吗？
Yeah, all right.
好吧
Tony, everything go okay?
东尼，没事吧？
Yeah, everything is roses.
嗯，一切顺利
Ernie, what time do you got?
恩尼，现在几点？
-Ten to.   -Ten to.
-五十分  -五十分
-Where is this guy, man?   -I gotta call Manny again.
-这家伙去哪了？  -我再打一次给曼尼
Sit down.
坐下
You don't tell me what to do here!
你敢告诉我怎么做！
-He's coming out.   -He's coming.
-他出来了  -他来了
-I don't give a fuck.   -It's him, man.
-我才不在乎  -是他
We do it in front of the United Nations.
我们在联合国前动手
That's how they want it.
那是他们的要求
I don't care where you blow him up.
我不在乎你在哪里摆平他
Tell me when, okay?
告诉我何时，知道吗？
You just tell me when. That's all I care about.
你只要告诉我何时就够了
I want you to stay thirty meters behind the car, okey?
我要你待在车后30公尺处
Thirty meters. No more.
30公尺，别太远
I heard you the first time.
你说一次我就听到了
One time. That's all you gotta tell me.
一次，你只要跟我说一次
I told you thirty meters.
我跟你说30公尺
This fucking guy, I'm telling you.
这个王八蛋，我告诉你
Look.Here he comes.
看，他来了
Where's he going?
他要去哪里？
What's he doing that way?
他为什么走那边？
What the fuck he doing?
他在搞什么？
What the fuck is that? Come here.
这是怎么回事？过来
You said she took the kids in the other car!
你说她带小孩坐另一辆车！
She did, every fucking day. I don't know what's going on.
是啊，每天都是，我也不知道是怎么回事
No fucking way. No fucking way. That's it!
他妈的不行，他妈的不行，算了！
Forget it!
住手！
We kill this guy alone. No wife, no kids.
我们只杀那家伙，不杀老婆，不杀小孩
No way. It Sosa says we do it now, we do it now.Let's do.
不行，索沙要我们现在动手，我们就现在动手，走吧
This fucking guy.
这个王八蛋
Okay, just stay behind him.
跟着他
Slowly, slowly.
慢点，慢点
Fuck you, you fucking vulture.
去你的，你他妈的秃鹰
Okay. Easy.
好，轻松点
Two little kids in the car. This is so fucking bad.
两个小孩在车里，真是他妈的糟
This is so fucking bad.
真是他妈的糟
You're losing them. Look! You're losing them!
你快跟丢了，看！你快跟丢了！
I see them, all right? I see them!
我看得到他们，好吗？我有看到！
Ten meters, ten meters!
十公尺，十公尺！
Move it. Move it!
快走，快走！
Shut the fuck up, okay?
闭上你的鸟嘴，好吗？
You don't have the guts to look them in the eye when you kill them.
你没胆面对面杀他们
You gotta hide with that shit...
只能够在这…
Shut your mouth.
闭嘴
He's getting up. Let's do it.
他起身了，动手吧
Make you feel good?
让你很爽吧？
Make you feel good to kill a mama and her kids? Make you feel big.
杀死妈妈跟小孩让你很爽吧？让你觉得自己很重要吧
Shut your mouth.
闭上你的嘴！
-Like you, big man!    -Fuck you!
-大人物啊！ -去你的！
What do you think I am?
你以为我是什么人？
You think I kill two kids and a woman?
你以为我会杀两个小孩跟母亲吗？
Fuck that! I don't need that shit in my life!
妈的！我这辈子没感觉这么糟过！
You die, motherfucker!
你去死吧，混蛋！
What do you think I am, huh?
你以为我是什么人？
You think I'm a fucking worm like you?
你以为我跟你一样下贱吗？
I told you, man! I told you, don't fuck with me!
我告诉你了！我告诉过你了，别惹毛我！
I told you, no fucking kids!
我告诉你，不准他妈的碰小孩！
No, but you wouldn't listen! You stupid fuck! Look at you now.
你就是不听！你这他妈的蠢猪！看看你现在什么样子！
Nick, where the fuck you been?
尼克，你他妈的跑哪去了？
On a delivery?
去送货？
Where the hell is Manny?
曼尼人呢？
I been calling all over. Where is he?
我到处在找他，他去哪了？
I don't know, Tony.
我不知道，东尼
He's been gone the last couple of days.
他已经几天没出现了
-He didn't say nothing.   -He's gone? What? Where?
-他什么都没说  -他走了？为什么？去哪里？
I left him in fucking charge, man! Where the fuck is he?
我他妈的让他掌理大局！他到底他妈的去哪了？
You can't trust nobody anymore!
真的谁都信不过！
I don't know, Tony. He just took off.
我不知道，东尼，他就这么走了
-He didn't say nothing.   -He took off?
-什么都没说  -他走了？
-Are you all right?   -No, I'm not all right! I'm pissed!
-你还好吗？  -不，我不好！我气死了！
When I get back there,
等我回去以后
I'll kick some ass all over the place!
我会踢得某人满地找牙！
-When you coming back?   -I'm coming back tonight!
-你什么时候回来？  -我今晚就回来！
This fucking cocksucker.
他妈的王八蛋
Tony, your mama called. Gina's gone.
东尼，你妈妈打过电话来，吉娜走了
-Gone? Where?   -She got to see you right away.
-走了？去哪里？ -她要立刻见你
Tell her I'll call her tonight.
告诉她我今晚会打电话给她
Listen to me. What about Elvie? She call?
听我说，艾薇呢？她有没有打电话来？
-No.  -No.
-没有 -没有
Okay, listen to me.
好，听我说
If she calls, just tell her I love her.
如果她打来，告诉她我爱她
Okay? Just tell her that.
知道吗？就这么跟她说
-You hear from Manny?    -No.
-有曼尼的消息吗？  -没有
Your mama called, she gotta see you.
你妈妈有打来，她要见你
Sosa's been ringing every half hour. He sounds pissed.
索沙每隔半小时就打来一次，听起来很生气的样子
-Get him on the phone. Elvie call?   -No.
-打给他，艾薇有打来吗？  -没有
You keep trying Manny. I want that cocksucker here.
你继续找曼尼，我要那混蛋来这里
-I want him here now! Okay?   -Okay.
-我现在就要他来！知道吗？  -知道了
Come on. Go ahead, get him! Let's go. Come on!
快点，去，去找他！走吧，快点！
Yeah? Mama. Yeah, I know.
是？妈妈，嗯，我知道
They told me.
他们跟我说了
Okay. I'm coming over.
我会过来
I'll be over to see you. I'll be over, yeah.
我会过来看你，我会过来
Put it on the speaker.
打开扩音器
What happened, Tony?
怎么一回事，东尼？
-Alex, how you doing?   -What happened?
-亚历克斯，你好吗？ -怎么一回事？
Oh, we had some problems.
遇到一点麻烦
-Alex?   -Tony, what happened?
-亚历克斯？  -东尼，到底怎么回事？
-We had a little problem.   -I heard.
-遇到一点麻烦  -我听说了
How you hear that?
你怎么知道的？
Our friend gave a speech at the UN.
我们的朋友在联合国发表了一篇演说
He was not supposed to give that speech.
他原本不该发表那份演说的
Well, your guy, Alberto, he's a piece of shit.
你的人，艾伯特是个混球
I told him to do something, he didn't listen,
我叫他做点事，他却不听话
so I canceled his contract.
我取消了他的合约
My partners and I are pissed off.
我的伙伴跟我都很火大
That's okay. No big deal.
没关系，没什么大不了的
There's other Albertos. We'll do it next month.
又不是只有一个艾伯特，我们下个月再干一次
No, Tony, you can't do that.
不，东尼，你不能这样做
They found what was under the car.
他们找到车底下的东西
Now our friend has got security up the ass.
现在我们的朋友受到严密的保安戒护
The heat will come down hard on my partners and me.
我跟我伙伴很快就会受到压力
There's not gonna be a next time,
没有下一次了
-you dumb cocksucker! You blew it!   -Take it easy when you talk to me.
-你这蠢猪！你搞砸了！  -你跟我说话小心点
I told you a long time ago, you fucking monkey, not to fuck me!
我老早就告诉过你，你这他妈的蠢蛋，别搞我！
Who the fuck you think you're talking to, huh?
你以为你他妈的在跟谁说话？
You want to fuck with...
你他妈的想…
Who the fuck you think I am, your fucking bellboy?
你他妈的以为我是谁，帮你开门的小弟吗？
You want to go to war? We take you to war, okay?
你想开战吗？那就开战，好啊？
Alex, you there? Hey!
亚历克斯，你还在在线吗？喂！
He's not there. Cálmate, man.
他挂线了，放松点，老兄
She got a place of her own. She don't tell me where.
她有自己的地方，她不跟我说在哪
One night, I follow her in a taxi.
有一晚，我坐出租车跟踪她
She goes to a fancy house in Coconut Grove.
她去了椰子岭的一栋大房子
-Where'd she get the money?    -You!
-她哪来的钱？  -你！
You were giving her the money! You see what you do to her?
是你给她钱的！你知道自己对她做了什么了吧？
-I don't give her that much money.   -You did!
-我没给她那么多钱  -你有！
-One time, $1,000 you gave her.   -Was a guy with her?
-有一次，你给了她一千元   -有个男人和她一起吗？
I don't know.
我不知道
There was this car in the driveway.
在车道上有一辆车
I know if I go there, she'll kill me.
我知道如果我过去，她会杀了我
-She's like you.   -Where's the place? Where is it?
-她跟你一样  -这地方在哪里？在哪里？
400 something...
四百多号…
Citrus Drive.
橙树街
-400 what?    -409, I think.
-四百多少？  -四百零九吧
You gotta talk to her, Antonio. She don't listen to me.
你一定要和她谈谈，安东尼奥，她不听我的
She says to me, "Mira, shut up!
她跟我说“笨蛋，闭嘴！
"Mind your own business."
“管好你自己的事”
Exactly like you do to me.
就像你对我一样
Ever since you came back, she's been getting this way.
自从你回来之后，她就变成那样
-I gotta go.   -Why do you have to hurt everything?
-我必须走了  -为什么你要破坏每样东西？
Why do you have to destroy
为什么你要破坏
everything that comes your way?
你身边的每样东西？
-409 Citrus Drive.   -Okay.
-409号橙树街  -好
-Tony, I can't find Manny anywhere.   -Fuck!
-东尼，我到处都找不到曼尼  -干！
Okay. Listen, boss, I'll try again.
老大，我会再试试
You stay here. Keep trying Manny, okay?
你留在这继续找曼尼，懂吗？
Tony.
东尼
We got married just yesterday. We were gonna surprise you.
我们昨天刚结婚，本来打算给你个惊喜的
Jesus, Tony.
老天，东尼
Tony, we gotta get outta here, man. We gotta get outta here.
东尼，快离开这里，老兄，我们必须快点离开
Go get Gina.
去带吉娜
No!
不！
No, Gina. Come on, Gina. No!
吉娜，走吧，吉娜，不！
God!
天哪！
Tony, we can't stay here. We gotta go.
东尼，我们不能在这，我们必须走了
We gotta get out of here.
我们一定要走了
Come on, Gina.
快点，吉娜
Here we go. It's gonna be okay.
走吧，没事的
-You got her?    -I got her.
-你扶好她了？  -我扶住了
No! This is Tony's place! Let me go!
不！这是东尼的地方！让我走！
We put some pills into her. She's gonna be all right, Tony.
我们喂她吃了药，她会没事的，东尼
She's cooling down. Right?
她安静下来了吗？
-She's gonna be fine. Just fine.   -Right.
-她会没事的，没事  -嗯
What are we gonna do now?
我们现在怎么办？
Do?
怎么办？
We're going to war.
我们开战了
That's what we're gonna do.
这就是我们的打算
We're gonna eat that Sosa for breakfast!
我们要吃了索沙！
Close that fucker down.
让那个王八蛋走投无路
Tony, take it easy.
东尼，放松点
All right, Ernie. Let's go.We'll take care of the house.
好吧，恩尼，我们走，去把房子处理好
Come on.
来吧
This cocksucker's gonna run all over you.
那个混蛋会毫不留情对你出手
Come on. I'll bury these cocksuckers.
我会杀了那些混蛋
We gotta get organized here.
我们要把这里整理好
Fuck! Manny.
干！曼尼
How the fuck I do that?
我为什么他妈的那么做？
How the fuck I do that, Manny?
我为什么他妈的那么做，曼尼？
Tony.
东尼
Gina.
吉娜
Is this what you want, Tony?
这就是你想要的吗，东尼？
You can't stand for another man to be touching me.
你不能忍受其它男人碰我
So you want me, Tony, huh?
所以你要我吗，东尼？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Is that it?
是这样吗？
Here I am, Tony.
我就在这里，东尼
I am all yours now, Tony, you see?
我是你的了，东尼，你看？
I'm all yours now.
我全都是你的了
Gina.
吉娜
You better come and get me now.
你最好现在就来上我
-All right. Come on.    -Come and get me.
-好啊，过来   -来上我啊
Come and get me.
来上我啊
You do it now before it's too late.
趁你现在还有机会
Oh, come on, Tony.
来啊，东尼
Fuck me.
干
Fuck me. Come on and just fuck me!
干，来上我啊！
Die!
死吧！
They're all over the place! Get out of here!
到处都是他们的人！快离开这里！
Gina.
吉娜
Come on. Look at your face. It's all dirty.
看看你的脸，真脏
Please talk to me.
拜托跟我说话
Don't be mad at me.
别生我的气
Please. Gina, come on.
拜托，吉娜，拜托
I love Manny, you know?
我爱曼尼，你知道吗？
I love him.
我爱他
And I love you, too, you know?
我也爱你，你知道吗？
Give me a smile.
笑一个
They're coming from everywhere!
四面八方都是他们的人！
Tony, open up! Open the fucking door!
东尼，开门！快打开他妈的门！
Please! Tony!
拜托！东尼！
Let me in, boss! Please!
让我进去，老大！拜托！
Tony, open the fucking door!
东尼，快打开他妈的门！
You wait here, okay? I'll be with you. I'll be back.
你在这里等一下，好吗？我很快回来陪你
You wait for me. I'm coming back.
你等我，我很快回来
Okay, Sosa. You want to fuck with me?
好，索沙，你要对付我？
You're fucking with the best!
你找错对象了！
You want to fuck with me?
你想对付我？
You cockroaches.
你这鼠辈
You want to play games? Okay, I play with you.
你要玩游戏？好，我就陪你玩
You wanna play rough?
你想玩得刺激点？
Say hello to my little friend!
跟我的小朋友打个招呼吧！
You want to play rough?
你想玩得刺激点？
There! You like that?
刺激吧！喜欢吗？
You want more?
还要吗？
You whores!
贱货！
Cowards!
懦夫！
Want to fuck with me?
想对付我？
Go ahead!
放马过来！
Come on!
来啊！
How do you like that, huh?
滋味如何？
You fucking maricón!
你这王八蛋！
You think you can take me?
你以为你能打赢我？
You need a fucking army if you gonna take me!
你得派出一个军队才有机会赢我！
You hear? Come on! I take you all to fucking hell!
听到了吗？来啊！我会让你们全部下地狱！
Who you think you fucking with? I'm Tony Montana!
你以为你是在对付谁？我可是东尼蒙大拿
You fuck with me, you fucking with the best!
你和我过不去，你找错对象了！
I'm still standing.
我还没倒下
Come on! I take your fucking bullet!
来啊！来射我啊！
You think you kill me with bullets?
你以为你的子弹能杀得死我？
I take your fucking bullets! Go ahead!
来射我啊！来啊！
这世界属于你
This film is dedicated to HOWARD HAWKS and BEN HECHT.
仅将此片向霍华霍金斯以及班赫克特致意